<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving
and Interchange DTD v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" dtd-version="1.2" article-type="other">
  <front>
    <article-meta>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>Item Construction Rules Revisited: Learnings from
Measurement of Latent Variables with Gold-Standard Items</article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0003-3676-9420</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Eichhorn</surname>
            <given-names>Kathryn</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Kathryn Eichhorn</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="conceptualization" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/conceptualization/">conceptualization</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="investigation" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/investigation/">investigation</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="resources" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/resources/">resources</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="data curation" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/data-curation/">data
curation</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – original draft" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-original-draft/">writing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff-1">a</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0002-0597-8708</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Bühner</surname>
            <given-names>Markus</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Markus Bühner</string-name>
          <email>buehner@lmu.de</email>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="formal analysis" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/formal-analysis/">formal
analysis</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="supervision" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/supervision/">supervision</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – original draft" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-original-draft/">writing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="lmu">b</xref>
          <xref ref-type="corresp" rid="cor-2">*</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0002-2388-553X</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Pargent</surname>
            <given-names>Florian</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Florian Pargent</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="formal analysis" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/formal-analysis/">formal
analysis</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="software" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/software/">software</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="validation" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/validation/">validation</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – review &amp; editing" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-review-editing/">editing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="lmu">b</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0002-6536-8266</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Saretzki</surname>
            <given-names>Janika</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Janika Saretzki</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – review &amp; editing" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-review-editing/">editing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="lmu">b</xref>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff-3">c</xref>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff-4">d</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0002-3389-1626</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Sust</surname>
            <given-names>Larissa</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Larissa Sust</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – review &amp; editing" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-review-editing/">editing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="lmu">b</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0009-0002-8872-0530</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Hauck</surname>
            <given-names>Jonas</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Jonas Hauck</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – review &amp; editing" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-review-editing/">editing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="regen">e</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0001-5808-8357</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Hilbert</surname>
            <given-names>Sven</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Sven Hilbert</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="conceptualization" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/conceptualization/">conceptualization</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="supervision" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/supervision/">supervision</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – review &amp; editing" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-review-editing/">editing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="regen">e</xref>
        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <aff id="aff-1">
        <institution content-type="dept">Institute of Psychology</institution>
        <institution-wrap>
          <institution>University of the Bundeswehr Munich</institution>
        </institution-wrap>
        <city>Neubiberg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </aff>
      <aff id="lmu">
        <institution content-type="dept">Department of Psychology</institution>
        <institution-wrap>
          <institution>LMU Munich</institution>
        </institution-wrap>
        <addr-line>Leopoldstr. 13</addr-line>
        <city>D-80802 Munich</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
        <postal-code>80802</postal-code>
      </aff>
      <aff id="aff-3">
        <institution content-type="dept">Department of Psychology</institution>
        <institution-wrap>
          <institution>University of Graz</institution>
        </institution-wrap>
        <city>Graz</city>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </aff>
      <aff id="aff-4">
        <institution-wrap>
          <institution>Charlotte Fresenius University of Psychology</institution>
        </institution-wrap>
        <city>Munich</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </aff>
      <aff id="regen">
        <institution content-type="dept">Faculty of Psychology</institution>
        <institution-wrap>
          <institution>University of Regensburg</institution>
        </institution-wrap>
        <city>Regensburg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </aff>
      <author-notes>
        <corresp id="cor-2">buehner@lmu.de</corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <history/>
      <permissions>
        <license license-type="creative-commons">
          <ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref>
        </license>
      </permissions>
      <abstract>
This article investigates whether gold-standard items are helpful for
questionnaire construction. Based on cognitive interviews
(<inline-formula><alternatives><tex-math><![CDATA[N]]></tex-math><mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"><mml:mi>N</mml:mi></mml:math></alternatives></inline-formula>
= 8) and a pilot study (<inline-formula><alternatives><tex-math><![CDATA[N]]></tex-math><mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"><mml:mi>N</mml:mi></mml:math></alternatives></inline-formula>
= 390) with an initial item set, three 12-item scales were constructed
to measure the physical traits of body height, body weight, and age. We
collected data on these scales using response formats with either two
(<inline-formula><alternatives><tex-math><![CDATA[N]]></tex-math><mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"><mml:mi>N</mml:mi></mml:math></alternatives></inline-formula>
= 921) or six (<inline-formula><alternatives><tex-math><![CDATA[N]]></tex-math><mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"><mml:mi>N</mml:mi></mml:math></alternatives></inline-formula>
= 933) categories. We also collected numeric self-reports of body
weight, body height, and age as gold-standard items. Confirmatory factor
analyses revealed that the gold-standard items did not consistently
exhibit the highest loading on their corresponding latent variable.
Furthermore, when controlling for the self-reported physical body
height, body weight, and age as gold-standard items, as well as gender,
we did not always find an interpretable, systematic residual variance.
Finally, the pattern of correlations between the latent variables did
not reflect the correlations between the self-reported gold-standard
items, suggesting that the item scales and the gold-standard items do
not have the same validity. While these results are consistent with
previous studies, our analyses also showed that items with two response
categories were at least as valid as those with six categories,
contradicting past recommendations. When constructing a questionnaire,
we would argue that the items intended to measure the latent variable
most directly should have the highest loading on that variable. If this
is not the case, the content validity is questionable at best. The
implications are that intensive cognitive pretesting is necessary.
Questionnaires with different response formats should be compared
empirically and hypotheses about which items best represent the latent
variable should be tested.
</abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
  <body>
    <p>
</p>
    <p>Psychological researchers typically develop questionnaires and use
latent variable modeling to test whether they measure the intended
psychological construct
(<xref alt="Holt et al., 2010" rid="ref-tenholtScaleConstructionEvaluation2010" ref-type="bibr">Holt
et al., 2010</xref>). According to the most applied test models (e.g.,
factor analytic models) especially item discrimination parameters are
interpreted as how well items correlate with the latent variable (see
<xref alt="Lord et al., 1968" rid="ref-lordStatisticalTheoriesMental1968" ref-type="bibr">Lord
et al., 1968</xref>). Highly correlated items with the latent variable
indicate that these items are more important to measure the latent
variable compared to items with lower correlations. Thus, the item
discrimination parameter is typically used to assess the quality of an
item measuring the latent variable.</p>
    <p>To assure that we obtain high item discrimination parameters it is
essential to start with a precise definition of the latent variable. The
definition is the starting point for deriving items with content
validity. The item construction is believed to be theoretically sound if
items are selected from a larger population of possible indicators of
the latent variable in a representative manner to achieve high content
validity and ensure that we measure the indented construct. Let us
assume that we try to measure the latent variable <italic>interpersonal
warmth</italic> with the following adjectives:
<italic>affectionate</italic>, <italic>friendly</italic>,
<italic>talkative</italic>, <italic>unprejudiced</italic>. We ask how
well each adjective describes yourself from <italic>not at all</italic>
(0) to <italic>fully and entirely</italic> (4) with five response
categories. If these items measure warmth, they should at least all
significantly correlate with the adjective warmth measured with the same
response format. Even more, the warmth item should have the highest
discrimination parameter conducting a factor analysis with empirical
data, otherwise a different construct is measured, e.g., friendliness,
in the case that the adjective <italic>friendly</italic> has the highest
loading on the latent variable. This can be seen as a robustness check
that the latent variable has the intended meaning. In the following
sections, we refer to such items as <italic>gold-standard
items</italic>.</p>
    <p>In this study, we construct scales for the “physical traits”
<italic>body height</italic>, <italic>body weight</italic>, and
<italic>age</italic> and compare them with a gold-standard item, that
is, the numerical self-report of the respective physical property. We
derive three assumptions that should hold if a valid measurement of the
mentioned latent variables is possible. We base these assumptions on the
relevant literature on previous studies, item wording, and response
categories, which we will outline in the next section.</p>
    <sec id="theoretical-background">
      <title>Theoretical Background</title>
      <sec id="evidence-using-gold-standard-items">
        <title>Evidence Using Gold-Standard Items</title>
        <p>To demonstrate the validity of psychological measurements and the
    practical utility of psychological measurement models, Bortolotti et
    al.
    (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>)
    compared psychological measurement with physical measurement. They
    constructed a scale with 27 items intended to assess body height.
    Using a response format with two response categories, participants
    were asked to respond to items such as “Do I think, I would do well
    in a basketball team?”
    (<xref alt="Bortolotti et al., 2013, p. 2350" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013" ref-type="bibr">Bortolotti
    et al., 2013, p. 2350</xref>). At the end of the scale, participants
    were asked to report their actual height in centimeters, the
    self-reported physical gold-standard item. The parameters estimated
    from the latent variable body height were then compared with the
    physical, gold-standard measurements. The results revealed a strong
    correlation (.86, not corrected for disattenuation) between the
    estimated person parameters derived from a two-parameter logistic
    model and the self-reported physical height. Still, the
    gold-standard item did not exhibit the highest loading on the scale
    (<xref alt="Bortolotti et al., 2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013" ref-type="bibr">Bortolotti
    et al., 2013</xref>). Van der Linden
    (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-vanderlindenUnidimensionalLogisticResponse2016" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>)
    also employed a height measurement based on items with two response
    categories (e.g., “I bump my head quite often.”, p. 27) to
    illustrate the usefulness of logistic item response models.
    According to the author, this approach is unusual, as body height
    appears to be a physical variable that can only be measured using a
    yardstick. However, differences in height influence behavior, making
    it quite plausible to view such behavioral indicators as proxies for
    body height and to derive a psychological measurement from them. The
    two examples suggest that, first, gold-standard items do not always
    have the highest loading on the latent variable. Second, measuring a
    “physical” latent variable might be a psychological representation
    of body height rather than a measure of physical body height.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="item-wording">
        <title>Item Wording</title>
        <p>One important aspect of item construction is item wording. In
    this context, Pargent et al.
    (<xref alt="2019" rid="ref-pargentCanMakeIt2019" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>)
    showed that the quality of item wording did, in fact, not impact
    model fit based on commonly used fit indices of confirmatory factor
    analyses. Sound item wording may not be crucial for achieving good
    model fit, but it clearly is for understanding the item correctly:
    For example, if a person does not correctly recognize an item with
    negative polarity, the person’s value on the scale is immediately
    over- or underestimated by a few points. In some cases, this can
    lead to considerable distortions in the test score. If a person does
    not understand the items correctly, their response cannot be valid,
    regardless of any model fit indicators (for an extreme example, see
    <xref alt="Maul, 2017" rid="ref-maulRethinking2017" ref-type="bibr">Maul,
    2017</xref>). Thus, it would be problematic to evaluate the quality
    of a questionnaire by solely looking at the model fit of the latent
    variable model, the discrimination parameters and/or reliability
    estimates. In this context, McNeish et al.
    (<xref alt="2018" rid="ref-mcneishThornyRelationMeasurement2018" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>)
    stated that good fit indices (e.g., Root Mean Square Error of
    Approximation, RMSEA; Standardized Root Mean Square Residual, SRMR;
    and the Comparative Fit Index, CFI) must be considered together with
    measurement quality (reliability) and the size of standardized
    factor loadings. They showed examples where all fit indices were
    excellent, but the standardized item loadings were .40, and another
    model where the fit indices were inadequate, but the factor loadings
    were .90. Thus, fit indices can be misleading without considering
    the quality of measurement.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="response-scale">
        <title>Response Scale</title>
        <p>Hilbert et al.
    (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-hilbertInfluenceResponseFormat2016" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>)
    presented initial evidence that different response scales might not
    measure the same latent variable. They found that the correlation
    (disattenuated for measurement error) between latent variables
    measured by identical items ranged only from .76 to .88 when using
    items with two versus five response categories and a visual analogue
    scale. The question arises: Which of these questionnaires measures
    the true construct? What is well known is how the number of response
    categories affects reliability estimates. A vast amount of
    literature compares different numbers of response categories for
    rating scale items. We quote some exemplary studies to demonstrate
    how complex and difficult it is to choose a reasonable number of
    response categories and highlight what we can conclude from their
    results. Preston &amp; Colman
    (<xref alt="2000" rid="ref-prestonOptimalNumberResponse2000" ref-type="bibr">2000</xref>)
    reported that two response categories exhibited the lowest
    retest-reliability and a relatively poor validity and discriminating
    power. They recommend applying rating scales with at least seven
    response categories. In contrast, Lee &amp; Paek
    (<xref alt="2014, p. 663" rid="ref-leeSearchOptimalNumber2014" ref-type="bibr">2014,
    p. 663</xref>) concluded that “caution should be made if a scale has
    only two response categories, but that limitation may be overcome by
    manipulating other scale features, namely, scale length or item
    discrimination”. Weijters et al.
    (<xref alt="2010" rid="ref-weijtersEffectRatingScale2010" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>)
    recommend rating scales with five fully labeled response categories
    for samples drawn from the general population. In their
    recommendations, the authors considered an extreme response style,
    responses to reversed items, and an acquiescence response style.
    However, Masuda et al.
    (<xref alt="2017" rid="ref-masudaRespondentsLowMotivation2017" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>)
    found that low-motivated persons tend to use the middle category,
    implying that a middle category is not advisable. Similarly, Bradley
    et al.
    (<xref alt="2015, p. 8" rid="ref-bradleyRatingScalesSurvey2015" ref-type="bibr">2015,
    p. 8</xref>) concluded from their study that “for constructing
    measures from survey responses, the inclusion of a neutral middle
    category distorts the data to the point where it is not possible to
    construct meaningful measures.” All in all, the reviewed literature
    suggests that to achieve high reliability, seven response categories
    seem the be useful, but there is also evidence to omit the middle
    category due to the inconsistent use of it. Thus, we infer that
    there is evidence to use rating scales with six response categories
    without a middle category.</p>
      </sec>
    </sec>
    <sec id="implications">
      <title>Implications</title>
      <p>We quote from a review on the application of Item Response Theory
  (IRT) models and factor analyses
  (<xref alt="Holt et al., 2010, p. 288" rid="ref-tenholtScaleConstructionEvaluation2010" ref-type="bibr">Holt
  et al., 2010, p. 288</xref>): “In our opinion, researchers could take
  far better advantage of their theoretical knowledge and/or
  expectations by incorporating their a priori knowledge of the items
  and scales in the analyses. This should be reflected 1) by a more
  frequent application of confirmatory techniques, especially in the
  construction of new scales and 2) by adding interpretability of
  factors and content of items to the criteria used for model
  evaluation.” Building on this summary statement, the aforementioned
  research and recommendations, we assess three physical “traits” to
  replicate and extend previous findings. First, we constructed scales
  for body height, body weight, and age. Second, we used items with two
  response categories to replicate the results of Bortolotti et al.
  (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>)
  for body height. Third, we applied an additional format containing six
  response categories without a middle category which low-motivated
  persons tend to overuse (e.g., see
  <xref alt="Masuda et al., 2017" rid="ref-masudaRespondentsLowMotivation2017" ref-type="bibr">Masuda
  et al., 2017</xref>). We aimed to investigate whether 1) the results
  of Bortolotti et al.
  (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>)
  hold true for body height and similar physical traits, and whether 2)
  there really is a psychological component in self-report
  questionnaires of physical traits as assumed by Van der Linden
  (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-vanderlindenUnidimensionalLogisticResponse2016" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>).
  Furthermore, we assumed that items with six response categories have
  higher reliability and thus, higher loadings and better validity than
  those with two response categories
  (<xref alt="Lee &amp; Paek, 2014" rid="ref-leeSearchOptimalNumber2014" ref-type="bibr">Lee
  &amp; Paek, 2014</xref>;
  <xref alt="Preston &amp; Colman, 2000" rid="ref-prestonOptimalNumberResponse2000" ref-type="bibr">Preston
  &amp; Colman, 2000</xref>;
  <xref alt="Weijters et al., 2010" rid="ref-weijtersEffectRatingScale2010" ref-type="bibr">Weijters
  et al., 2010</xref>). The concrete assumptions underlying our research
  are the following:<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">1</xref></p>
      <list list-type="bullet">
        <list-item>
          <p><italic>Assumption 1:</italic> From a theoretical point of
      view, the self-reported physical body height, body weight, and age
      as the self-reported gold-standard items should have the highest
      factor loading (which is equivalent to a high correlation between
      the latent variable and the item applying a one-factor model)
      compared to other questionnaire items measuring the respective
      physical trait.</p>
        </list-item>
        <list-item>
          <p><italic>Assumption 2:</italic> The measurement of physical
      traits with questionnaire items should have a psychological
      component because the self-reported physical measurement and
      gender (as there are gender differences in perception, see
      <xref alt="McCreary, 2002" rid="ref-mccrearyGenderAgeDifferences2002" ref-type="bibr">McCreary,
      2002</xref>) cannot fully explain the item responses. Systematic
      correlated residuals should remain.</p>
        </list-item>
        <list-item>
          <p><italic>Assumption 3a, b:</italic> The correlational pattern
      between the latent variables for the physical traits should
      correspond to the correlation of the self-reported gold-standard
      items (3a) and the factor loadings and reliability estimates
      should be higher for scales with 6-point response categories
      compared to 2-point response categories (3b).</p>
        </list-item>
      </list>
      <p>
  </p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="methods">
      <title>Methods</title>
      <p>All materials (reproducible manuscript, analysis code, datasets,
  codebooks, questionnaires) for this manuscript are openly available on
  the Open Science Framework (OSF) at
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://osf.io/p7492/">https://osf.io/p7492/</ext-link>.
  A Quarto Manuscripts website presenting the manuscript and electronic
  supplementary materials is hosted at
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://florianpargent.github.io/gold-standard-items/">https://florianpargent.github.io/gold-standard-items/</ext-link>.</p>
      <sec id="item-construction">
        <title>Item Construction</title>
        <p>First, we constructed items for the physical characteristics of
    body height, body weight, and age. Age was defined as chronological
    age or age in years, corresponding to the time elapsed since a
    person’s birth
    (<xref alt="Montepare &amp; Lachman, 1989" rid="ref-montepareYouReOnly1989" ref-type="bibr">Montepare
    &amp; Lachman, 1989</xref>;
    <xref alt="Schwall, 2012" rid="ref-schwallDefiningAgeUsing2012" ref-type="bibr">Schwall,
    2012</xref>). Height was defined as the height of an upright person
    from the sole of the foot to the top of the head in centimeters, and
    body weight as the physical mass of a person in kilograms
    (<xref alt="Martin, 1929" rid="ref-martinAnthropometrieAnleitungSelbstaendigen1929" ref-type="bibr">Martin,
    1929</xref>). The initial items were developed by 124 psychology
    students (deductive item construction,
    <xref alt="Burisch, 1984" rid="ref-burischApproachesPersonalityInventory1984" ref-type="bibr">Burisch,
    1984</xref>) and 24 persons (prototype approach, see
    <xref alt="Broughton, 1984" rid="ref-broughtonPrototypeStrategyConstruction1984" ref-type="bibr">Broughton,
    1984</xref>) who deviated from the German population mean at least
    one standard deviation in the relevant characteristics (separately
    for women and men). The 24 persons were asked to think of
    prototypical behaviors for each construct to assess the whole
    spectrum of the latent variable. This process resulted in an initial
    set of 138 items (response categories were not tested). In a second
    step, we examined how these items were interpreted and whether they
    were connected to additional concepts unrelated to the constructs
    using cognitive interviews. We conducted interviews with a length of
    two to three hours and applied various cognitive procedures,
    including probing, paraphrasing, concurrent-think-aloud, and
    retrospective-think-aloud
    (<xref alt="Prüfer &amp; Rexroth, 1996" rid="ref-prueferVerfahrenEvaluationSurvey1996" ref-type="bibr">Prüfer
    &amp; Rexroth, 1996</xref>,
    <xref alt="2005" rid="ref-prueferKognitiveInterviews2005" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>).
    The literature on cognitive interviews recommends five to 30
    interviews but indicates that the most serious problems can already
    be identified with a small number of interviews
    (<xref alt="Willis, 2005" rid="ref-willisCognitiveInterviewing2005" ref-type="bibr">Willis,
    2005</xref>). The interviews were conducted with 8 people from the
    target group (4 women and 4 men) aged between 21 and 77
    (<italic>M</italic> = 44.50, <italic>SD</italic> = 20.78). The level
    of education ranged from high school diploma to university degree.
    After the cognitive interviews, misleading items were reformulated
    or eliminated
    (<xref alt="Faulbaum et al., 2009" rid="ref-faulbaumWasIstGute2009" ref-type="bibr">Faulbaum
    et al., 2009</xref>), resulting in 61 remaining items. In a third
    step, these 61 items were pilot tested online on a new sample, which
    initially consisted of 456 people. However, we excluded 66 subjects
    because they had not completed the questionnaire, resulting in a
    sample of 390 participants aged between 18 and 77 years
    (<italic>M</italic> = 31.91, <italic>SD</italic> = 12.82), including
    302 women (77.44 %) and 88 men (22.56 %). The level of education was
    distributed as follows: 0 % no school leaving certificate, 3.33 %
    secondary school leaving certificate/elementary school or
    equivalent, 17.18 % secondary school or equivalent, 35.90 %
    vocational baccalaureate or high school diploma, 40.77 % college
    degree or university degree, 2.82 % doctorate or habilitation. Out
    of all respondents, 95.38 % stated German as their native language.
    Based on these survey responses, we excluded items if a) their main
    item loading was not on the intended factor, b) their main and
    secondary loadings were almost equal, or c) they had loading below
    or equal to .30. Additionally, if (d) items had very similar
    content, items with lower loadings were excluded. More details on
    the process of item construction can be found in Eichhorn
    (<xref alt="2019" rid="ref-eichhornItem2019" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>).
    We reproduced the exploratory factor analyses, item total
    correlations and reliability estimates that were computed in the
    final item selection stage and report them in our electronic
    supplementary materials. Based on these criteria 12 final items were
    selected for each physical trait (see
    <xref alt="Table 5" rid="tbl-5">Table 5</xref>).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn2">2</xref>
    For each of the three questionnaires, two versions were created –
    one with a 6-point scale combining verbal endpoints (“does not
    apply” to “applies”, only endpoints were labeled) with full numeric
    anchoring (numbers from 1 to 6) and one with a 2-point scale
    combining verbal labels (“does not apply” and “applies”) with
    numeric anchors (numbers 0 and 1).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="statistical-analysis">
        <title>Statistical Analysis</title>
        <p>All analyses were conducted in R version 4.5.1 (2025-06-13). A
    full list of software versions can be found in
    (<xref alt="apx-3?" rid="ref-apx-3" ref-type="bibr"><bold>apx-3?</bold></xref>).
    The data were analyzed using confirmatory factor analyses using the
    package <italic>lavaan</italic>
    (<xref alt="Rosseel, 2012" rid="ref-R-lavaan" ref-type="bibr">Rosseel,
    2012</xref>). We used the weighted least squares, mean and variance
    adjusted (WLSMV) estimator, treating the questionnaire items as
    ordinal and the self-reported physical gold-standard items body
    height, body weight, and age as continuous variables. First, we
    specified (1) unidimensional models without any error correlations,
    and (2) models with one latent variable and correlated errors. In
    both models the gold-standard items and the other 12 items were
    specified as indicators of a single latent variable. Second, to test
    whether there is a latent variable while controlling for the
    gold-standard item and gender, (3) models were specified with a
    single latent variable where the questionnaire items were
    additionally predicted by the gold-standard item and gender. Third,
    to compare the correlations between the latent variables with the
    correlations between the gold-standard items, (4) full three factor
    models without correlated errors were estimated, in which only the
    questionnaire items load on their respective latent variable and
    correlations are estimated between the latent variables, between the
    gold-standard items, and between the latent variables and the
    gold-standard items. We also conducted reliability analyses using
    the package <italic>MBESS</italic>
    (<xref alt="Kelley, 2023" rid="ref-R-MBESS" ref-type="bibr">Kelley,
    2023</xref>) and report McDonald’s Omega as a reliability estimate
    of internal consistency for each scale.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sample">
        <title>Sample</title>
        <p>The total sample of our main study consisted of 1854 participants
    aged between 18 and 97 years (<italic>M</italic> = 32.70,
    <italic>SD</italic> = 16.01), including 1036 women (56%) and 818 men
    (44%). The overall sample consisted of two independent subsamples,
    which were divided into the 2-point and 6-point response format
    conditions.</p>
        <p>Participants were recruited in trains, colleges, universities,
    adult education centers, fitness studios and various public places
    in Germany and Austria in November and December 2017. Participation
    was voluntary and without reimbursement. Each participant was handed
    a paper and pencil questionnaire, alternating between the 2-point
    and 6-point response scale versions. When a participant handed back
    the questionnaire, the facilitator immediately checked for missing
    values, in which case the participant was politely asked to complete
    the missing questions. With this procedure, we achieved complete
    responses for all questionnaires.</p>
        <p><xref alt="Table 1" rid="tbl-1">Table 1</xref> shows the
    distribution of gender, level of education, native language, and age
    within the two conditions. As expected based on the randomization
    procedure, the two subsamples are very similar. Due to the
    left-skewed age distribution and outlier values, the median is
    reported as a measure of the central tendency instead of the
    mean.</p>
        <fig id="tbl-1">
          <caption>
            <p>Table 1: Sample characteristics within response
      category conditions</p>
          </caption>
          <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="manuscript_files/figure-jats/tbl-1-1.png"/>
        </fig>
        <p>
    </p>
      </sec>
    </sec>
    <sec id="results">
      <title>Results</title>
      <sec id="assumption-1-the-self-reported-physical-body-height-weight-and-age-should-have-the-highest-loadings-on-their-latent-variables.">
        <title><italic>Assumption 1:</italic> The self-reported physical
    body height, weight, and age should have the highest loadings on
    their latent variables.</title>
        <p><xref alt="Table 2" rid="tbl-2">Table 2</xref> displays the
    measurement models for the three scales for body height, body
    weight, and age for two and six response categories each.</p>
        <fig id="tbl-2">
          <caption>
            <p>Table 2: Standardized item loadings (correlations with
      the latent variable) for two and six response
      categories</p>
          </caption>
          <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="manuscript_files/figure-jats/tbl-2-1.png"/>
        </fig>
        <p>
    </p>
        <p>Overall, both response formats produced similar loading patterns,
    but those with two response categories obtained slightly higher
    loadings compared to six response categories for most items.
    Questionnaires with two response categories showed slightly better
    fit indices than those with six categories. All model fits were
    within the expected range for psychological questionnaires
    (<xref alt="Goretzko et al., 2024" rid="ref-goretzkoEvaluatingModelFit2024" ref-type="bibr">Goretzko
    et al., 2024</xref>). In particular, the fit indices for the
    questionnaires on body height and weight with two response
    categories showed the best fit.</p>
        <p>For the body height scales, the self-reported physical height
    loaded higher or similarly high on the latent variables compared to
    the questionnaire items. However, this pattern slightly differed for
    the weight and age scales, where several items loaded substantially
    higher on the latent variable than the physical items: For weight,
    the items 4 (“I am obese.”) and 5 (“I weigh a lot.”) had especially
    high loadings on the latent variable for the questionnaires with two
    and six response categories. For age, item 7 (“I have already lived
    most of my life.”) had especially high loadings on the latent
    variable for the questionnaires with two and six response
    categories. The item loadings for the weight and age scales suggest
    that the gold-standard items were not essential for measuring the
    latent variable.</p>
        <p>Even after allowing for correlated errors as suggested by
    standard modification indices, the loading patterns did not improve
    (see <xref alt="Table 5" rid="tbl-5">Table 5</xref>). Loading
    patterns with and without modifications were correlated at .98
    (<italic>p</italic> &lt; .001) across all questionnaires (body
    height, body weight, age) and response variants (two and six
    categories).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="assumption-2-the-measurement-should-have-a-psychological-component-and-the-item-responses-cannot-be-fully-explained-by-the-self-reported-physical-measurement-and-gender.-a-systemic-residual-should-remain-when-corrected-for-self-reported-physical-height-and-gender.">
        <title><italic>Assumption 2:</italic> The measurement should have a
    psychological component, and the item responses cannot be fully
    explained by the self-reported physical measurement and gender. A
    systemic residual should remain when corrected for self-reported
    physical height and gender.</title>
        <p><xref alt="Table 3" rid="tbl-3">Table 3</xref> displays item
    loadings on the latent variable when controlling for the
    self-reported physical item and self-reported gender.</p>
        <fig id="tbl-3">
          <caption>
            <p>Table 3: Standardized item loadings on the latent
      variable for two and six categories controlling for the
      self-reported physical item and self-reported gender</p>
          </caption>
          <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="manuscript_files/figure-jats/tbl-3-1.png"/>
        </fig>
        <p>
    </p>
        <p>For body height, we obtained low item loadings on the latent
    variable but high regression weights with the gold-standard item of
    physical body height. In particular, the third item (“Chairs and
    tables are usually too low for me.”) exhibited the highest loading
    on the latent variable for both response formats. In contrast, item
    11 (“I have to stand at the front of group photos so that I can be
    seen clearly.”) and item 12 (“When I hug other people in greeting, I
    have to bend downwards.”) were best predicted by the self-reported
    physical body height for both response
    formats.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn3">3</xref> This pattern does not
    convincingly confirm the existence of a psychological latent height
    variable after controlling for the self-reported physical item and
    gender.</p>
        <p>For body weight, the items with high loadings on the latent
    variable also exhibited high associations with the self-reported
    physical body weight. Item 4 (“I am obese.”) had the highest loading
    on the latent variable for both response formats. Item 5 (“I weigh a
    lot.”) was explained best by the self-reported physical body weight.
    Item 9 (“I have a lot of space between the armrests in airplane
    seats.”) had a low loading on the latent variable but was moderately
    predicted by the self-reported physical body weight for both
    response formats. Notably, item 11 (“If I have the choice between
    the elevator and the stairs, I take the elevator.”) was not related
    to either the self-reported physical item or the latent variable for
    both response formats, indicating that it may represent a more
    health-related perspective. Taken together, the resulting latent
    weight variable is hard to interpret.</p>
        <p>For age, we observed the biggest discrepancy between items with
    high loadings on the latent variable and items best predicted by
    self-reported physical age. Item 3 (“I have a lot of life
    experience.”) and item 9 (“I have years of work experience.”) did
    not load on the latent variable after controlling for physical age
    and gender but were predicted by self-reported physical age for both
    response formats. In contrast, the three items most prototypical of
    the latent variable were item 2 (“Over time, my mental capacity has
    decreased.”), item 5 (“Over time, my memory has deteriorated.”), and
    item 4 (“Over time, my ability to react has decreased.”) for both
    response formats. Thus, the latent variable might be interpreted as
    mental age, but not all items have a substantial loading on this
    general factor.</p>
        <p>When looking at self-reported gender, there are moderate
    standardized regression weights for some items of body height (e.g.,
    item 8 “Pants are often so short for me.”) and body weight (e.g.,
    item 6 “I need to lose weight.”). These items may cause problems
    when applied to both men and women (differential item functioning;
    see
    <xref alt="Hilbert et al., 2022" rid="ref-hilbertWhatMeasureEmpirical2022" ref-type="bibr">Hilbert
    et al., 2022</xref>, for a comparable case). Notably, there are only
    non-significant low standardized regression weights of self-reported
    gender predicting age items.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="assumption-3a-b-the-correlational-pattern-between-the-latent-variables-for-the-construct-should-correspond-to-the-correlations-of-the-self-reported-gold-standard-items-and-the-validity-should-be-higher-for-the-6-point-response-categories-compared-to-the-2-point-response-categories.">
        <title>Assumption 3a, b: The correlational pattern between the
    latent variables for the construct should correspond to the
    correlations of the self-reported gold-standard items and the
    validity should be higher for the 6-point response categories
    compared to the 2-point response categories.</title>
        <p>As depicted in <xref alt="Table 4" rid="tbl-4">Table 4</xref>,
    the correlations between the latent variables do not match those
    between the self-reported physical items. While height and age
    showed relatively similar low correlations, the physical
    correlations of weight and age were overestimated by the
    correlations between the latent variables and the physical
    correlations between height and weight were underestimated. Most
    notably, correlations did not differ substantially between the
    questionnaires with two and with six response categories.
    Descriptively, the physical correlations seemed to be reproduced by
    the latent correlations slightly better for the two response
    categories. However, reliability estimates (Omega) were lower for
    two response categories compared to six response categories.</p>
        <fig id="tbl-4">
          <caption>
            <p>Table 4: Correlations between the latent variables
      body height, body weight and age, reliability estimates, and
      correlations between the corresponding self-reported physical
      items for two and six response categories</p>
          </caption>
          <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="manuscript_files/figure-jats/tbl-4-1.png"/>
        </fig>
        <p>
    </p>
      </sec>
    </sec>
    <sec id="discussion">
      <title>Discussion</title>
      <sec id="summary">
        <title>Summary</title>
        <p>The goal of this study was to find out whether gold-standard
    items have the highest loadings on the corresponding latent
    variable. This was investigated using items with two and six
    response categories which measure these physical traits. The results
    reveal that this is only an exception, and two response categories
    perform not necessarily worse than six response categories regarding
    validity and reliability. Gold-standard items might help to ensure
    the interpretation of the latent variable. The choice of the
    response format should be based on empirical testing and extensive
    cognitive interviews. It seems not sufficient to take advice from
    the literature on how to choose the number of response categories to
    optimize reliability. The benefit of gold-standard items will be
    discussed in the following sections.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="gold-standard-items">
        <title>Gold-Standard Items</title>
        <p>Gold-standard items did not work as theoretically expected in
    this study. However, we still believe they are important. Only the
    gold-standard item for body height – for six, not for two response
    categories – had the highest loading on the latent variable.
    Bortolotti et al.
    (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>),
    who previously applied the same procedure with two response
    categories to investigate a gold-standard item for body height,
    found a correlation of .86 with body height. This correlation pretty
    much matches our correlation with the latent variable. The
    correlation was slightly higher for our 2-response category scale
    (.87) compared to our 6-response category scale (.86), but there
    were also items which had descriptively equal or higher correlations
    (biserial correlations) with the sum score than the self-reported
    physical item (Pearson correlation). This might be because we
    reported a latent correlation corrected for disattenuation, and our
    scale had 12 instead of 27 items. Nevertheless, our results depict a
    conceptual replication of Bortolotti et al.
    (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>)
    with a different questionnaire.</p>
        <p>The results differed for the other latent variables of body
    weight and age, which exhibited lower correlations between the
    latent variable and their gold-standard items. This seems
    problematic as these items were designed to be the “gold” measure of
    the latent variable and should ensure a consistent interpretation.
    Thus, we should carefully reflect what this finding means for item
    construction for psychological scales of non-physical traits. If
    this basic requirement is not met, even for traits that seem rather
    straightforward to measure, what about more complex constructs? To
    avoid a misleading interpretation of a latent variable, it might be
    very helpful to formulate a priori hypotheses about the importance
    of the constructed items as we did here to test the construct
    validity of a test. If we, for example, want to measure
    <italic>interpersonal warmth</italic> as a big five facet and
    construct items that describe this facet, an item that most directly
    measures warmth should have its highest loading on the latent
    variable, otherwise the interpretation of the latent variable is not
    justified.</p>
        <p>We must be aware, that general model fit does not prove how well
    items are formulated (see
    <xref alt="Pargent et al., 2019" rid="ref-pargentCanMakeIt2019" ref-type="bibr">Pargent
    et al., 2019</xref>). Model fit also does not reveal if the applied
    items are helpful to measure the latent variable. Model fit simply
    compares a model implied variance/covariance matrix with an
    empirical variance/covariance matrix. In this study, the a priori
    most suitable items did not have always the highest discrimination
    parameters or loadings. Thus, simply selecting items according to
    their loadings and letting the factor analysis decide which item is
    good or not is probably insufficient. There must be an item content
    loading fit.</p>
        <p>The reliability estimate of the questionnaire informs us only
    about the precision of measurement and not whether our measurement
    is valid. This does not necessarily contradict attempts to choose
    items based on reliability (e.g., see
    <xref alt="Zijlmans et al., 2019" rid="ref-zijlmansItemScoreReliabilitySelection2019" ref-type="bibr">Zijlmans
    et al., 2019</xref>) since items must have high loadings to achieve
    high reliability estimates for the scale.</p>
        <p>Thus, we suggest using gold-standard items as described above. It
    should be noted, however, that it is critical not to implement the
    gold-standard item in the final scale since we would then create a
    part-whole relationship. This no desirable situation since all test
    models (classical and IRT models) assume that the probability of a
    positive response of a person to an item should not depend on this
    person’s response to any other item
    (<xref alt="Debelak &amp; Koller, 2020" rid="ref-debelakTestingLocalIndependence2020" ref-type="bibr">Debelak
    &amp; Koller, 2020</xref>).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="physical-traits-as-psychological-variables">
        <title>Physical Traits as Psychological Variables</title>
        <p>Previous hints suggest that measuring physical attributes through
    psychological questionnaires is not always connected to a
    psychological latent variable guiding behavior
    (<xref alt="Hilbert et al., 2022" rid="ref-hilbertWhatMeasureEmpirical2022" ref-type="bibr">Hilbert
    et al., 2022</xref>;
    <xref alt="Van der Linden, 2016" rid="ref-vanderlindenUnidimensionalLogisticResponse2016" ref-type="bibr">Van
    der Linden, 2016</xref>). Similarly, in our study, it remained
    unclear if a psychological latent variable beyond body height and
    weight was measured and how such a latent variable could be
    interpreted. Only for age there was a latent variable, which can be
    interpreted as cognitive or psychological age
    (<xref alt="Barak &amp; Schiffman, 1981" rid="ref-barakCognitiveAgeNonchronological1981" ref-type="bibr">Barak
    &amp; Schiffman, 1981</xref>). Furthermore, it seems helpful to
    include additional items, that are not intended to be measured but
    may further explain the item responses of interest, such as gender
    or items from the nomological net to reveal possible dependencies
    and to decide whether these dependencies are in line with the
    definition of the latent variables.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="number-of-categories">
        <title>Number of Categories</title>
        <p>As expected, reliability estimates were higher for scales with
    six response categories compared to two categories. The results with
    regard to model fit and validity, indicated as correlations between
    latent variables compared to the correlation between gold-standard
    items, are mixed. Some fit indices suggested slightly better fit for
    items with two response categories and some for six categories. The
    same holds true for the differences between the correlations of the
    gold-standard items and the correlations of the latent variables.
    Except for reliability, the study revealed no clear picture to
    choose between two or six response categories. Hilbert et al.
    (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-hilbertInfluenceResponseFormat2016" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>,
    <xref alt="2022" rid="ref-hilbertWhatMeasureEmpirical2022" ref-type="bibr">2022</xref>)
    showed that the same items with a different number of response
    categories do not measure the same latent variable. This result
    highlights that the choice of the number of response categories
    constructing a questionnaire should be based on an empirical study
    comparing several options accompanied by an intensive cognitive
    pretesting phase and not only based on the literature which focuses
    on maximal reliability.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="recommendations">
        <title>Recommendations</title>
        <p>The results presented here should prompt reflection and
    reconsideration of standard procedures of item construction in
    psychology. First, it may be helpful to more strongly consider
    content validity when developing items. Items that either represent
    a kind of gold-standard with specific hypotheses about the ranking
    of the loadings or construct-divergent items that (in)validate the
    items intended to measure a latent variable should be included in
    the construction process. Revisiting the example of
    <italic>interpersonal warmth</italic> as a personality facet, such
    additional validation items could, for example, measure warmth
    itself or openness. An openness scale or marker items that show high
    correlations with these warmth items should not be included in the
    final scale but only used for validation purposes. These demands are
    not entirely new, but should be newly emphasized based on the
    results of our analyses, calling for more stringent item
    construction approaches. Second, the choice of an optimal response
    scale may not be as clear-cut as previously suggested (e.g.,
    <xref alt="Lee &amp; Paek, 2014" rid="ref-leeSearchOptimalNumber2014" ref-type="bibr">Lee
    &amp; Paek, 2014</xref>). We found that items with two response
    categories were not per se unfavorable, as often suggested in the
    literature. While our binary scales obtained lower reliability
    estimates as expected (see
    <xref alt="Preston &amp; Colman, 2000" rid="ref-prestonOptimalNumberResponse2000" ref-type="bibr">Preston
    &amp; Colman, 2000</xref>;
    <xref alt="Revilla et al., 2014" rid="ref-revillaChoosingNumberCategories2014" ref-type="bibr">Revilla
    et al., 2014</xref>), other results regarding validity and model fit
    were mixed. Since reliability is easier to control for by adding
    more suitable items, construct validity seems to be the stronger
    argument when choosing the number of response categories. In sum, we
    believe that decisions on response scales should be empirically
    founded, especially in high stakes situations (e.g., clinical
    diagnosis or personnel selection), comparing alternative numbers of
    response categories in pilot testing. In this context, it is
    important to recognize that the number of response categories can
    influence what latent variables are measured (see
    <xref alt="Hilbert et al., 2016" rid="ref-hilbertInfluenceResponseFormat2016" ref-type="bibr">Hilbert
    et al., 2016</xref>,
    <xref alt="2022" rid="ref-hilbertWhatMeasureEmpirical2022" ref-type="bibr">2022</xref>).
    Thus, comparing the construct validity of questionnaires differing
    in the number of response categories is essential. Nevertheless, it
    remains necessary to subject response scales to intensive cognitive
    pretesting to determine a suitable number of categories. On the one
    hand, cognitive interviews can reveal when single categories are
    systematically overlooked by respondents lacking information or
    cognitive capacity to differentiate categories. On the other hand,
    cognitive pretests help assess participants’ cognitive load, which
    should always be kept in mind. For example, two-point scales, which
    are commonly criticized, have previously been shown to require less
    effort from the respondents
    (<xref alt="Hilbert et al., 2016" rid="ref-hilbertInfluenceResponseFormat2016" ref-type="bibr">Hilbert
    et al., 2016</xref>).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="conclusion">
        <title>Conclusion</title>
        <p>Based on the results of the present study, we advocate the
    inclusion of gold-standard items, i.e. items that are supposed to
    measure the intended construct most directly, to check the
    interpretation of latent variables in the construction of
    psychological questionnaires. In addition, for questionnaires that
    are used to make particularly important decisions, we recommend
    empirically testing the choice of response format, considering both
    validity and reliability to make a well-founded decision. The
    pre-selection of response formats should include cognitive pretests
    of the items.</p>
        <p>
    </p>
      </sec>
    </sec>
    <sec id="references">
      <title>References</title>
    </sec>
    <sec id="apx-1">
      <title>CFA models with correlated errors</title>
      <fig id="tbl-5">
        <caption>
          <p>Table 5: Latent variable loadings for two and six
    response categories with correlated errors</p>
        </caption>
        <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="manuscript_files/figure-jats/tbl-5-1.png"/>
      </fig>
    </sec>
    <sec id="apx-2">
      <title>Item translations</title>
      <p>
        <bold>Table B2</bold>
      </p>
      <p>Translated items used in this study</p>
      <table-wrap>
        <table>
          <colgroup>
            <col width="26%"/>
            <col width="74%"/>
          </colgroup>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th align="left">Item</th>
              <th align="left">Item wording (Original wording in
          German)</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 1</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I keep my head down when I walk through
          doors. (Ich ziehe den Kopf ein wenn ich durch Türen
          gehe.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 2</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">In the middle of a crowd, I can see over most
          other people. (Inmitten einer Menschenmenge kann ich über die
          meisten anderen Menschen hinwegblicken.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 3</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">Chairs and tables are usually too low for me.
          (Stühle und Tische sind meistens zu niedrig für mich.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 4</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">In the supermarket, I can reach the things on
          the top shelf without any problems. (Im Supermarkt komme ich
          ohne Probleme an die Sachen im obersten Regal.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 5</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">When I drive a car that was previously driven
          by someone else, I usually have to push the seat backwards.
          (Wenn ich ein Auto fahre, das vorher jemand anderes gefahren
          hat, muss ich üblicherweise den Sitz nach hinten
          schieben.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 6</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">When I stretch out straight in hotel beds, my
          feet overlap. (Wenn ich mich in Hotelbetten gerade ausstrecke,
          dann stehen meine Füße über.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 7</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">On airplanes, I bump my knees against the
          seat in front of me. (Im Flugzeug stoße ich mit den Knien am
          Vordersitz an.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 8</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">Pants are often too short for me. (Hosen sind
          mir häufig zu kurz.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 9</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I need a chair if I want to get things from
          the top shelf. (Ich brauche einen Stuhl, wenn ich Sachen aus
          dem obersten Regal holen möchte.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 10</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I have to look up when I talk to other
          people. (Wenn ich mich mit anderen Menschen unterhalte muss
          ich nach oben schauen.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 11</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I have to stand at the front of group photos
          so that I can be seen clearly. (Ich muss mich bei Gruppenfotos
          nach vorne stellen, damit ich gut zu sehen bin.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Height 12</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">When I hug other people in greeting, I have
          to bend downwards. (Wenn ich andere Menschen zur Begrüßung
          umarme, muss ich mich nach unten beugen.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 1</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I am often afraid that chairs will give way
          under me. (Ich habe oft Angst, dass Stühle unter mir
          nachgeben.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 2</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">Other people may think that I sit on the sofa
          in the evening and eat chocolate and potato chips.
          (Möglicherweise denken andere Menschen von mir, dass ich
          abends auf dem Sofa sitze und Schokolade und Chips esse.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 3</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I have a wide waistband when it comes to
          pants. (Bei Hosen habe ich eine große Bundweite.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 4</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I am obese. (Ich bin dick.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 5</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I weigh a lot. (Ich wiege viel.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 6</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I need to lose weight. (Ich müsste
          abnehmen.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 7</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">My pants have a small waistband. (Meine Hosen
          haben eine kleine Bundweite.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 8</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I am good at squeezing through narrow gaps.
          (Ich kann mich gut durch enge Spalten quetschen.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 9</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I have a lot of space between the armrests in
          airplane seats. (Zwischen den Armlehnen in Flugzeugsitzen habe
          ich viel Platz.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 10</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I take up a lot of space in the elevator. (Im
          Aufzug nehme ich viel Platz ein.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 11</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">If I have the choice between the elevator and
          the stairs, I take the elevator. (Wenn ich die Wahl habe
          zwischen Aufzug und Treppe, dann nehme ich den Aufzug.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Weight 12</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I should eat less. (Ich sollte weniger
          essen.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 1</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I have physical ailments. (Ich habe
          körperliche Gebrechen.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 2</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">Over time, my mental capacity has decreased.
          (Im Laufe der Zeit hat meine geistige Leistungsfähigkeit
          abgenommen.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 3</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I have a lot of life experience. (Ich habe
          viel Lebenserfahrung.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 4</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">Over time, my ability to react has decreased.
          (Im Laufe der Zeit hat meine Reaktionsfähigkeit
          abgenommen.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 5</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">Over time, my memory has deteriorated. (Im
          Laufe der Zeit hat meine Merkfähigkeit abgenommen.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 6</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I worry a lot about getting older. (Ich mache
          mir viele Gedanken über das Älterwerden.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 7</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I have already lived most of my life. (Den
          größten Teil meines Lebens habe ich bereits gelebt.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 8</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I find it increasingly difficult to follow
          technical developments. (Ich habe zunehmend Schwierigkeiten
          technischen Weiterentwicklungen zu folgen.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 9</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I have years of work experience. (Ich habe
          jahrelange Berufserfahrung.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 10</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">My whole life still lies ahead of me. (Mein
          ganzes Leben liegt noch vor mir.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 11</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I used to be more willing to take risks.
          (Früher war ich risikofreudiger.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="left">
                <bold>Age 12</bold>
              </td>
              <td align="left">I carry out everyday activities more slowly
          than before. (Ich verrichte Alltagstätigkeiten langsamer als
          früher.)</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </table-wrap>
      <p><italic>Note:</italic> Original wording in German shown in
  parenthesis.</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="apx-3">
      <title>Software versions</title>
      <p>Quarto
  (<xref alt="Allaire et al., 2025" rid="ref-allaireQuarto2025" ref-type="bibr">Allaire
  et al., 2025</xref>) version 1.7.32 and the extension apaquarto
  (<xref alt="Schneider, 2025" rid="ref-schneiderApaquarto2025" ref-type="bibr">Schneider,
  2025</xref>) were used together with RStudio
  (<xref alt="Posit team, 2025" rid="ref-positRstudio2025" ref-type="bibr">Posit
  team, 2025</xref>) to build the manuscript and the manuscript website.
  R (Version 4.5.1;
  <xref alt="R Core Team, 2025b" rid="ref-R-base" ref-type="bibr">R Core
  Team, 2025b</xref>) and the R-packages <italic>corx</italic> (Version
  1.0.7.2;
  <xref alt="Conigrave, 2023" rid="ref-R-corx" ref-type="bibr">Conigrave,
  2023</xref>), <italic>dplyr</italic> (Version 1.1.4;
  <xref alt="Wickham et al., 2023" rid="ref-R-dplyr" ref-type="bibr">Wickham
  et al., 2023</xref>), <italic>flextable</italic> (Version 0.9.9;
  <xref alt="Gohel &amp; Skintzos, 2024" rid="ref-R-flextable" ref-type="bibr">Gohel
  &amp; Skintzos, 2024</xref>), <italic>forcats</italic> (Version 1.0.0;
  <xref alt="Wickham, 2023a" rid="ref-R-forcats" ref-type="bibr">Wickham,
  2023a</xref>), <italic>foreign</italic> (Version 0.8.90;
  <xref alt="R Core Team, 2025a" rid="ref-R-foreign" ref-type="bibr">R
  Core Team, 2025a</xref>), <italic>ggplot2</italic> (Version 3.5.2;
  <xref alt="Wickham, 2016" rid="ref-R-ggplot2" ref-type="bibr">Wickham,
  2016</xref>), <italic>lavaan</italic> (Version 0.6.19;
  <xref alt="Rosseel, 2012" rid="ref-R-lavaan" ref-type="bibr">Rosseel,
  2012</xref>), <italic>lubridate</italic> (Version 1.9.4;
  <xref alt="Grolemund &amp; Wickham, 2011" rid="ref-R-lubridate" ref-type="bibr">Grolemund
  &amp; Wickham, 2011</xref>), <italic>MBESS</italic> (Version 4.9.3;
  <xref alt="Kelley, 2023" rid="ref-R-MBESS" ref-type="bibr">Kelley,
  2023</xref>), <italic>papaja</italic> (Version 0.1.3;
  <xref alt="Aust &amp; Barth, 2024" rid="ref-R-papaja" ref-type="bibr">Aust
  &amp; Barth, 2024</xref>), <italic>psych</italic> (Version 2.5.6;
  <xref alt="William Revelle, 2025" rid="ref-R-psych" ref-type="bibr">William
  Revelle, 2025</xref>), <italic>purrr</italic> (Version 1.1.0;
  <xref alt="Wickham &amp; Henry, 2025" rid="ref-R-purrr" ref-type="bibr">Wickham
  &amp; Henry, 2025</xref>), <italic>readr</italic> (Version 2.1.5;
  <xref alt="Wickham, Hester, et al., 2024" rid="ref-R-readr" ref-type="bibr">Wickham,
  Hester, et al., 2024</xref>), <italic>semTools</italic> (Version
  0.5.7;
  <xref alt="Jorgensen et al., 2025" rid="ref-R-semTools" ref-type="bibr">Jorgensen
  et al., 2025</xref>), <italic>stringr</italic> (Version 1.5.1;
  <xref alt="Wickham, 2023b" rid="ref-R-stringr" ref-type="bibr">Wickham,
  2023b</xref>), <italic>tibble</italic> (Version 3.3.0;
  <xref alt="Müller &amp; Wickham, 2023" rid="ref-R-tibble" ref-type="bibr">Müller
  &amp; Wickham, 2023</xref>), <italic>tidyr</italic> (Version 1.3.1;
  <xref alt="Wickham, Vaughan, et al., 2024" rid="ref-R-tidyr" ref-type="bibr">Wickham,
  Vaughan, et al., 2024</xref>), <italic>tidyverse</italic> (Version
  2.0.0;
  <xref alt="Wickham et al., 2019" rid="ref-R-tidyverse" ref-type="bibr">Wickham
  et al., 2019</xref>) and <italic>tinylabels</italic> (Version 0.2.5;
  <xref alt="Barth, 2025" rid="ref-R-tinylabels" ref-type="bibr">Barth,
  2025</xref>) were used for data analysis.
  Some dependencies are not included in this list but can be found in
  the <monospace>renv.lock</monospace> file in our online
  repository.</p>
    </sec>
  </body>
  <back>
    <ref-list>
      <title/>
      <ref id="ref-maulRethinking2017">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Maul</surname>
              <given-names>Andrew</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Rethinking traditional methods of survey validation</article-title>
          <source>Measurement: Interdisciplinary Research and Perspectives</source>
          <publisher-name>Routledge</publisher-name>
          <year iso-8601-date="2017">2017</year>
          <volume>15</volume>
          <issue>2</issue>
          <uri>https://doi.org/10.1080/15366367.2017.1348108</uri>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/15366367.2017.1348108</pub-id>
          <fpage>51</fpage>
          <lpage>69</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-eichhornItem2019">
        <element-citation publication-type="thesis">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Eichhorn</surname>
              <given-names>Kathryn</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Item und skala: Empirische untersuchungen zur gültigkeit psychologischer messungen anhand physikalischer merkmale</article-title>
          <publisher-name>Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München</publisher-name>
          <year iso-8601-date="2019">2019</year>
          <uri>http://nbn-resolving.de/urn:nbn:de:bvb:19-236286</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-schneiderApaquarto2025">
        <element-citation publication-type="software">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Schneider</surname>
              <given-names>William Joel</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>apaquarto</article-title>
          <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
          <uri>https://github.com/wjschne/apaquarto</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-positRstudio2025">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <string-name>Posit team</string-name>
          </person-group>
          <source>RStudio: Integrated development environment for r</source>
          <publisher-name>Posit Software, PBC</publisher-name>
          <publisher-loc>Boston, MA</publisher-loc>
          <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
          <uri>http://www.posit.co/</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-allaireQuarto2025">
        <element-citation publication-type="software">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Allaire</surname>
              <given-names>J. J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Teague</surname>
              <given-names>Charles</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Scheidegger</surname>
              <given-names>Carlos</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Xie</surname>
              <given-names>Yihui</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Dervieux</surname>
              <given-names>Christophe</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Woodhull</surname>
              <given-names>Gordon</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Quarto</article-title>
          <year iso-8601-date="2025-04">2025</year>
          <month>04</month>
          <uri>https://github.com/quarto-dev/quarto-cli</uri>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.5960048</pub-id>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Bortolotti</surname>
              <given-names>Silvana Ligia Vincenzi</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Tezza</surname>
              <given-names>Rafael</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>De Andrade</surname>
              <given-names>Dalton Francisco</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bornia</surname>
              <given-names>Antonio Cezar</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>De Sousa Júnior</surname>
              <given-names>Afonso Farias</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Relevance and advantages of using the item response theory</article-title>
          <source>Quality &amp; Quantity</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2013-06">2013</year>
          <month>06</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>47</volume>
          <issue>4</issue>
          <issn>0033-5177, 1573-7845</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11135-012-9684-5</pub-id>
          <fpage>2341</fpage>
          <lpage>2360</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-bradleyRatingScalesSurvey2015">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Bradley</surname>
              <given-names>Kelly D.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Peabody</surname>
              <given-names>Michael R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Akers</surname>
              <given-names>Kathryn S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Knutson</surname>
              <given-names>Nichole M.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Rating Scales in Survey Research: Using the Rasch model to illustrate the middle category measurement flaw</article-title>
          <source>Survey Practice</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2015-05">2015</year>
          <month>05</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>8</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>2168-0094</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.29115/SP-2015-0001</pub-id>
          <fpage>1</fpage>
          <lpage>12</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-broughtonPrototypeStrategyConstruction1984">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Broughton</surname>
              <given-names>Ross</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>A prototype strategy for construction of personality scales.</article-title>
          <source>Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="1984-12">1984</year>
          <month>12</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>47</volume>
          <issue>6</issue>
          <issn>1939-1315, 0022-3514</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.47.6.1334</pub-id>
          <fpage>1334</fpage>
          <lpage>1346</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-burischApproachesPersonalityInventory1984">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Burisch</surname>
              <given-names>Matthias</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Approaches to personality inventory construction: A comparison of merits.</article-title>
          <source>American Psychologist</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="1984-03">1984</year>
          <month>03</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>39</volume>
          <issue>3</issue>
          <issn>1935-990X, 0003-066X</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1037/0003-066X.39.3.214</pub-id>
          <fpage>214</fpage>
          <lpage>227</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-debelakTestingLocalIndependence2020">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Debelak</surname>
              <given-names>Rudolf</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Koller</surname>
              <given-names>Ingrid</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Testing the Local Independence Assumption of the Rasch Model With Q3 -Based Nonparametric Model Tests</article-title>
          <source>Applied Psychological Measurement</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2020-03">2020</year>
          <month>03</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>44</volume>
          <issue>2</issue>
          <issn>0146-6216, 1552-3497</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/0146621619835501</pub-id>
          <fpage>103</fpage>
          <lpage>117</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-faulbaumWasIstGute2009">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Faulbaum</surname>
              <given-names>Frank</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Prüfer</surname>
              <given-names>Peter</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Rexroth</surname>
              <given-names>Margrit</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Was ist eine gute Frage?</source>
          <publisher-name>VS Verlag für Sozialwissenschaften</publisher-name>
          <publisher-loc>Wiesbaden</publisher-loc>
          <year iso-8601-date="2009">2009</year>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <isbn>978-3-531-15824-2 978-3-531-91441-1</isbn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/978-3-531-91441-1</pub-id>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-goretzkoEvaluatingModelFit2024">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Goretzko</surname>
              <given-names>David</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Siemund</surname>
              <given-names>Karik</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sterner</surname>
              <given-names>Philipp</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Evaluating Model Fit of Measurement Models in Confirmatory Factor Analysis</article-title>
          <source>Educational and Psychological Measurement</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2024-02">2024</year>
          <month>02</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>84</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>0013-1644, 1552-3888</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/00131644231163813</pub-id>
          <fpage>123</fpage>
          <lpage>144</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-hilbertInfluenceResponseFormat2016">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Hilbert</surname>
              <given-names>Sven</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Küchenhoff</surname>
              <given-names>Helmut</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sarubin</surname>
              <given-names>Nina</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Toyo Nakagawa</surname>
              <given-names>Tristan</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bühner</surname>
              <given-names>Markus</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>The influence of the response format in a personality questionnaire: An analysis of a dichotomous, a Likert-type, and a visual analogue scale</article-title>
          <source>TPM - Testing, Psychometrics, Methodology in Applied Psychology</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2016">2016</year>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>23</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>1972-6325</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4473/TPM23.1.1</pub-id>
          <fpage>3</fpage>
          <lpage>24</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-hilbertWhatMeasureEmpirical2022">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Hilbert</surname>
              <given-names>Sven</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Pargent</surname>
              <given-names>Florian</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kraus</surname>
              <given-names>Elisabeth</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Naumann</surname>
              <given-names>Felix</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Eichhorn</surname>
              <given-names>Kathryn</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ungar</surname>
              <given-names>Patrizia</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bühner</surname>
              <given-names>Markus</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>What’s the measure? An empirical investigation of self-ratings on response scales</article-title>
          <source>International Journal of Social Research Methodology</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2022-01">2022</year>
          <month>01</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>25</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>1364-5579, 1464-5300</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/13645579.2020.1839163</pub-id>
          <fpage>59</fpage>
          <lpage>78</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-leeSearchOptimalNumber2014">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Lee</surname>
              <given-names>Jihyun</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Paek</surname>
              <given-names>Insu</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>In Search of the Optimal Number of Response Categories in a Rating Scale</article-title>
          <source>Journal of Psychoeducational Assessment</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2014-10">2014</year>
          <month>10</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>32</volume>
          <issue>7</issue>
          <issn>0734-2829, 1557-5144</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/0734282914522200</pub-id>
          <fpage>663</fpage>
          <lpage>673</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-lordStatisticalTheoriesMental1968">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Lord</surname>
              <given-names>Frederic M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Novick</surname>
              <given-names>Melvin R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Birnbaum</surname>
              <given-names>Allan</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lord</surname>
              <given-names>Frederic M.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Statistical theories of mental test scores</source>
          <publisher-name>Addison-Wesley</publisher-name>
          <publisher-loc>Reading, Mass.</publisher-loc>
          <year iso-8601-date="1968">1968</year>
          <edition>2. print</edition>
          <isbn>978-0-201-04310-5</isbn>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-martinAnthropometrieAnleitungSelbstaendigen1929">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Martin</surname>
              <given-names>Rudolf</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Anthropometrie: Anleitung Zu Selbständigen Anthropologischen Erhebungen</source>
          <publisher-name>Springer Berlin / Heidelberg</publisher-name>
          <publisher-loc>Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher-loc>
          <year iso-8601-date="1929">1929</year>
          <edition>2nd ed</edition>
          <isbn>978-3-662-31474-6 978-3-662-31681-8</isbn>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-masudaRespondentsLowMotivation2017">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Masuda</surname>
              <given-names>Shinya</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sakagami</surname>
              <given-names>Takayuki</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kawabata</surname>
              <given-names>Hideaki</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kijima</surname>
              <given-names>Nobuhiko</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hoshino</surname>
              <given-names>Takahiro</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Respondents with low motivation tend to choose middle category: Survey questions on happiness in Japan</article-title>
          <source>Behaviormetrika</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2017-07">2017</year>
          <month>07</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>44</volume>
          <issue>2</issue>
          <issn>0385-7417, 1349-6964</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s41237-017-0026-8</pub-id>
          <fpage>593</fpage>
          <lpage>605</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-mccrearyGenderAgeDifferences2002">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>McCreary</surname>
              <given-names>Donald</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Gender and Age Differences in the Relationship Between Body Mass Index and Perceived Weight: Exploring the Paradox</article-title>
          <source>International Journal of Men’s Health</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2002-01">2002</year>
          <month>01</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>1</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>1532-6306, 1933-0278</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3149/jmh.0101.31</pub-id>
          <fpage>31</fpage>
          <lpage>42</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-mcneishThornyRelationMeasurement2018">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>McNeish</surname>
              <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>An</surname>
              <given-names>Ji</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hancock</surname>
              <given-names>Gregory R.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>The Thorny Relation Between Measurement Quality and Fit Index Cutoffs in Latent Variable Models</article-title>
          <source>Journal of Personality Assessment</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2018-01">2018</year>
          <month>01</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>100</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>0022-3891, 1532-7752</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/00223891.2017.1281286</pub-id>
          <fpage>43</fpage>
          <lpage>52</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-montepareYouReOnly1989">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Montepare</surname>
              <given-names>Joann M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lachman</surname>
              <given-names>Margie E.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>"You’re only as old as you feel": Self-perceptions of age, fears of aging, and life satisfaction from adolescence to old age.</article-title>
          <source>Psychology and Aging</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="1989-03">1989</year>
          <month>03</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>4</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>1939-1498, 0882-7974</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1037/0882-7974.4.1.73</pub-id>
          <fpage>73</fpage>
          <lpage>78</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-pargentCanMakeIt2019">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Pargent</surname>
              <given-names>Florian</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hilbert</surname>
              <given-names>Sven</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Eichhorn</surname>
              <given-names>Kathryn</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bühner</surname>
              <given-names>Markus</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Can’t Make it Better nor Worse: An Empirical Study About the Effectiveness of General Rules of Item Construction on Psychometric Properties</article-title>
          <source>European Journal of Psychological Assessment</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2019-11">2019</year>
          <month>11</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>35</volume>
          <issue>6</issue>
          <issn>1015-5759, 2151-2426</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1027/1015-5759/a000471</pub-id>
          <fpage>891</fpage>
          <lpage>899</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-prestonOptimalNumberResponse2000">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Preston</surname>
              <given-names>Carolyn C</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Colman</surname>
              <given-names>Andrew M</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Optimal number of response categories in rating scales: Reliability, validity, discriminating power, and respondent preferences</article-title>
          <source>Acta Psychologica</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2000-03">2000</year>
          <month>03</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>104</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>00016918</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0001-6918(99)00050-5</pub-id>
          <fpage>1</fpage>
          <lpage>15</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-revillaChoosingNumberCategories2014">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Revilla</surname>
              <given-names>Melanie A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Saris</surname>
              <given-names>Willem E.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Krosnick</surname>
              <given-names>Jon A.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Choosing the Number of Categories in Agree–Disagree Scales</article-title>
          <source>Sociological Methods &amp; Research</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2014-02">2014</year>
          <month>02</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>43</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>0049-1241, 1552-8294</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/0049124113509605</pub-id>
          <fpage>73</fpage>
          <lpage>97</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-schwallDefiningAgeUsing2012">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Schwall</surname>
              <given-names>Alexander R.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Defining Age and Using Age-Relevant Constructs</source>
          <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
          <year iso-8601-date="2012-03">2012</year>
          <month>03</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/oxfordhb/9780195385052.013.0080</pub-id>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-vanderlindenUnidimensionalLogisticResponse2016">
        <element-citation publication-type="chapter">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Van der Linden</surname>
              <given-names>Wim J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Unidimensional logistic response models</article-title>
          <source>Handbook of item response theory, volume one: models</source>
          <person-group person-group-type="editor">
            <name>
              <surname>Van der Linden</surname>
              <given-names>Wim J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <publisher-name>Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC</publisher-name>
          <publisher-loc>Boca Raton, FL</publisher-loc>
          <year iso-8601-date="2016">2016</year>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1201/9781315374512</pub-id>
          <fpage>13</fpage>
          <lpage>30</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-weijtersEffectRatingScale2010">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Weijters</surname>
              <given-names>Bert</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Cabooter</surname>
              <given-names>Elke</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Schillewaert</surname>
              <given-names>Niels</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>The effect of rating scale format on response styles: The number of response categories and response category labels</article-title>
          <source>International Journal of Research in Marketing</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2010-09">2010</year>
          <month>09</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>27</volume>
          <issue>3</issue>
          <issn>01678116</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ijresmar.2010.02.004</pub-id>
          <fpage>236</fpage>
          <lpage>247</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-willisCognitiveInterviewing2005">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Willis</surname>
              <given-names>Gordon</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Cognitive Interviewing</source>
          <publisher-name>SAGE Publications, Inc.</publisher-name>
          <publisher-loc>2455 Teller Road, Thousand Oaks California 91320 United States of America</publisher-loc>
          <year iso-8601-date="2005">2005</year>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <isbn>978-0-7619-2804-1 978-1-4129-8365-5</isbn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4135/9781412983655</pub-id>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-zijlmansItemScoreReliabilitySelection2019">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Zijlmans</surname>
              <given-names>Eva A. O.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Tijmstra</surname>
              <given-names>Jesper</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Van Der Ark</surname>
              <given-names>L. Andries</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sijtsma</surname>
              <given-names>Klaas</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Item-Score Reliability as a Selection Tool in Test Construction</article-title>
          <source>Frontiers in Psychology</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2019-01">2019</year>
          <month>01</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <day>03</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>9</volume>
          <issn>1664-1078</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2018.02298</pub-id>
          <fpage>2298</fpage>
          <lpage/>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-barakCognitiveAgeNonchronological1981">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Barak</surname>
              <given-names>Benny</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Schiffman</surname>
              <given-names>Leon G.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Cognitive age: A nonchronological age variable.</article-title>
          <source>Advances in Consumer Research</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="1981">1981</year>
          <volume>8</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>0098-9258</issn>
          <fpage>602</fpage>
          <lpage>606</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-tenholtScaleConstructionEvaluation2010">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Holt</surname>
              <given-names>Janke C. ten</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Duijn</surname>
              <given-names>Marijtje A. J. van</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Boomsma</surname>
              <given-names>Anne</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Scale construction and evaluation in practice: A review of factor analysis versus item response theory applications.</article-title>
          <source>Psychological Test and Assessment Modeling</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2010">2010</year>
          <volume>52</volume>
          <issue>3</issue>
          <issn>2190-0507(Electronic),2190-0493(Print)</issn>
          <fpage>272</fpage>
          <lpage>297</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-prueferVerfahrenEvaluationSurvey1996">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Prüfer</surname>
              <given-names>Peter</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Rexroth</surname>
              <given-names>Margrit</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Verfahren zur evaluation von survey-fragen: Ein überblick</source>
          <publisher-name>Zentrum für Umfragen, Methoden und Analysen -ZUMA-</publisher-name>
          <publisher-loc>Mannheim</publisher-loc>
          <year iso-8601-date="1996">1996</year>
          <volume>1996/05</volume>
          <fpage>34</fpage>
          <lpage/>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-prueferKognitiveInterviews2005">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Prüfer</surname>
              <given-names>Peter</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Rexroth</surname>
              <given-names>Margrit</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Kognitive interviews</source>
          <publisher-name>Zentrum für Umfragen, Methoden und Analysen -ZUMA-</publisher-name>
          <publisher-loc>Mannheim</publisher-loc>
          <year iso-8601-date="2005">2005</year>
          <volume>15</volume>
          <fpage>26</fpage>
          <lpage/>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-base">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <string-name>R Core Team</string-name>
          </person-group>
          <source>R: A language and environment for statistical computing</source>
          <publisher-name>R Foundation for Statistical Computing</publisher-name>
          <publisher-loc>Vienna, Austria</publisher-loc>
          <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
          <uri>https://www.R-project.org/</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-corx">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Conigrave</surname>
              <given-names>James</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Corx: Create and format correlation matrices</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
          <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=corx</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-dplyr">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wickham</surname>
              <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>François</surname>
              <given-names>Romain</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Henry</surname>
              <given-names>Lionel</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Müller</surname>
              <given-names>Kirill</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Vaughan</surname>
              <given-names>Davis</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Dplyr: A grammar of data manipulation</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
          <uri>https://dplyr.tidyverse.org</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-forcats">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wickham</surname>
              <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Forcats: Tools for working with categorical variables (factors)</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
          <uri>https://forcats.tidyverse.org/</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-foreign">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <string-name>R Core Team</string-name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Foreign: Read data stored by ’minitab’, ’s’, ’SAS’, ’SPSS’, ’stata’, ’systat’, ’weka’, ’dBase’, ...</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
          <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=foreign</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-ggplot2">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wickham</surname>
              <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>ggplot2: Elegant graphics for data analysis</source>
          <publisher-name>Springer-Verlag New York</publisher-name>
          <year iso-8601-date="2016">2016</year>
          <isbn>978-3-319-24277-4</isbn>
          <uri>https://ggplot2.tidyverse.org</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-lavaan">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Rosseel</surname>
              <given-names>Yves</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>lavaan: An R package for structural equation modeling</article-title>
          <source>Journal of Statistical Software</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2012">2012</year>
          <volume>48</volume>
          <issue>2</issue>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.18637/jss.v048.i02</pub-id>
          <fpage>1</fpage>
          <lpage>36</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-lubridate">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Grolemund</surname>
              <given-names>Garrett</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wickham</surname>
              <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Dates and times made easy with lubridate</article-title>
          <source>Journal of Statistical Software</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2011">2011</year>
          <volume>40</volume>
          <issue>3</issue>
          <uri>https://www.jstatsoft.org/v40/i03/</uri>
          <fpage>1</fpage>
          <lpage>25</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-MBESS">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Kelley</surname>
              <given-names>Ken</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>MBESS: The MBESS r package</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
          <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=MBESS</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-purrr">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wickham</surname>
              <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Henry</surname>
              <given-names>Lionel</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Purrr: Functional programming tools</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
          <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=purrr</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-readr">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wickham</surname>
              <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hester</surname>
              <given-names>Jim</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bryan</surname>
              <given-names>Jennifer</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Readr: Read rectangular text data</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
          <uri>https://readr.tidyverse.org</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-semTools">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Jorgensen</surname>
              <given-names>Terrence D.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Pornprasertmanit</surname>
              <given-names>Sunthud</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Schoemann</surname>
              <given-names>Alexander M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Rosseel</surname>
              <given-names>Yves</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>semTools: Useful tools for structural equation modeling</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
          <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=semTools</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-stringr">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wickham</surname>
              <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Stringr: Simple, consistent wrappers for common string operations</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
          <uri>https://stringr.tidyverse.org</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-tibble">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Müller</surname>
              <given-names>Kirill</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wickham</surname>
              <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Tibble: Simple data frames</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
          <uri>https://tibble.tidyverse.org/</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-tidyr">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wickham</surname>
              <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Vaughan</surname>
              <given-names>Davis</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Girlich</surname>
              <given-names>Maximilian</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Tidyr: Tidy messy data</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
          <uri>https://tidyr.tidyverse.org</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-tidyverse">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wickham</surname>
              <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Averick</surname>
              <given-names>Mara</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bryan</surname>
              <given-names>Jennifer</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chang</surname>
              <given-names>Winston</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>McGowan</surname>
              <given-names>Lucy D’Agostino</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>François</surname>
              <given-names>Romain</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Grolemund</surname>
              <given-names>Garrett</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hayes</surname>
              <given-names>Alex</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Henry</surname>
              <given-names>Lionel</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hester</surname>
              <given-names>Jim</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kuhn</surname>
              <given-names>Max</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Pedersen</surname>
              <given-names>Thomas Lin</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Miller</surname>
              <given-names>Evan</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bache</surname>
              <given-names>Stephan Milton</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Müller</surname>
              <given-names>Kirill</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ooms</surname>
              <given-names>Jeroen</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Robinson</surname>
              <given-names>David</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Seidel</surname>
              <given-names>Dana Paige</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Spinu</surname>
              <given-names>Vitalie</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Takahashi</surname>
              <given-names>Kohske</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Vaughan</surname>
              <given-names>Davis</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wilke</surname>
              <given-names>Claus</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Woo</surname>
              <given-names>Kara</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yutani</surname>
              <given-names>Hiroaki</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Welcome to the tidyverse</article-title>
          <source>Journal of Open Source Software</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2019">2019</year>
          <volume>4</volume>
          <issue>43</issue>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.21105/joss.01686</pub-id>
          <fpage>1686</fpage>
          <lpage/>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-flextable">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Gohel</surname>
              <given-names>David</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Skintzos</surname>
              <given-names>Panagiotis</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Flextable: Functions for tabular reporting</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
          <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=flextable</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-papaja">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Aust</surname>
              <given-names>Frederik</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Barth</surname>
              <given-names>Marius</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>papaja: Prepare reproducible APA journal articles with R Markdown</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
          <uri>https://github.com/crsh/papaja</uri>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.32614/CRAN.package.papaja</pub-id>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-tinylabels">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Barth</surname>
              <given-names>Marius</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <source>tinylabels: Lightweight variable labels</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
          <uri>https://cran.r-project.org/package=tinylabels</uri>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.32614/CRAN.package.tinylabels</pub-id>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-R-psych">
        <element-citation publication-type="book">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <string-name>William Revelle</string-name>
          </person-group>
          <source>Psych: Procedures for psychological, psychometric, and personality research</source>
          <publisher-name>Northwestern University</publisher-name>
          <publisher-loc>Evanston, Illinois</publisher-loc>
          <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
          <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=psych</uri>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
    </ref-list>
    <fn-group>
      <fn id="fn1">
        <label>1</label>
        <p>The data presented in this manuscript has
    previously been analyzed in the German dissertation thesis of the
    first author
    (<xref alt="Eichhorn, 2019" rid="ref-eichhornItem2019" ref-type="bibr">Eichhorn,
    2019</xref>). As part of the dissertation, a preregistration was
    published at
    <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://osf.io/cz3uv/?view_only=9cac02db231b48629fea9ae53c3038b9">https://osf.io/cz3uv/?view_only=9cac02db231b48629fea9ae53c3038b9</ext-link>
    that differs from the analyses reported in the current publication.
    The results of the preregistered analyses are reported in Eichhorn
    (<xref alt="2019" rid="ref-eichhornItem2019" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>).</p>
      </fn>
      <fn id="fn2">
        <label>2</label>
        <p>Compared to the pilot test, one height and one
    weight item were slightly reworded to simplify the wording and
    reduce similarities with other items in the scale.</p>
      </fn>
      <fn id="fn3">
        <label>3</label>
        <p>Note that although the models for height
    (controlling for the physical item and gender) estimated some
    absolute standardized loadings greater than 1, all models converged
    and the diagnostics used by the <italic>lavaan</italic> package
    (<xref alt="Rosseel, 2012" rid="ref-R-lavaan" ref-type="bibr">Rosseel,
    2012</xref>) did not report any problems.</p>
      </fn>
    </fn-group>
  </back>
  <sub-article article-type="notebook" id="nb-5-nb-article">
    <front-stub>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>Item Construction Rules Revisited: Learnings from
Measurement of Latent Variables with Gold-Standard Items</article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0003-3676-9420</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Eichhorn</surname>
            <given-names>Kathryn</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Kathryn Eichhorn</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="conceptualization" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/conceptualization/">conceptualization</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="investigation" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/investigation/">investigation</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="resources" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/resources/">resources</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="data curation" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/data-curation/">data
curation</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – original draft" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-original-draft/">writing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff-1-nb-article">a</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0002-0597-8708</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Bühner</surname>
            <given-names>Markus</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Markus Bühner</string-name>
          <email>buehner@lmu.de</email>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="formal analysis" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/formal-analysis/">formal
analysis</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="supervision" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/supervision/">supervision</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – original draft" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-original-draft/">writing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="lmu-nb-article">b</xref>
          <xref ref-type="corresp" rid="cor-2-nb-article">*</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0002-2388-553X</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Pargent</surname>
            <given-names>Florian</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Florian Pargent</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="formal analysis" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/formal-analysis/">formal
analysis</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="software" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/software/">software</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="validation" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/validation/">validation</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – review &amp; editing" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-review-editing/">editing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="lmu-nb-article">b</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0002-6536-8266</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Saretzki</surname>
            <given-names>Janika</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Janika Saretzki</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – review &amp; editing" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-review-editing/">editing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="lmu-nb-article">b</xref>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff-3-nb-article">c</xref>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff-4-nb-article">d</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0002-3389-1626</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Sust</surname>
            <given-names>Larissa</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Larissa Sust</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – review &amp; editing" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-review-editing/">editing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="lmu-nb-article">b</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0009-0002-8872-0530</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Hauck</surname>
            <given-names>Jonas</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Jonas Hauck</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – review &amp; editing" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-review-editing/">editing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="regen-nb-article">e</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">0000-0001-5808-8357</contrib-id>
          <name>
            <surname>Hilbert</surname>
            <given-names>Sven</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Sven Hilbert</string-name>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="conceptualization" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/conceptualization/">conceptualization</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="supervision" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/supervision/">supervision</role>
          <role vocab="https://credit.niso.org" vocab-term="writing – review &amp; editing" vocab-term-identifier="https://credit.niso.org/contributor-roles/writing-review-editing/">editing</role>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="regen-nb-article">e</xref>
        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <aff id="aff-1-nb-article">
        <institution content-type="dept">Institute of Psychology</institution>
        <institution-wrap>
          <institution>University of the Bundeswehr Munich</institution>
        </institution-wrap>
        <city>Neubiberg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </aff>
      <aff id="lmu-nb-article">
        <institution content-type="dept">Department of Psychology</institution>
        <institution-wrap>
          <institution>LMU Munich</institution>
        </institution-wrap>
        <addr-line>Leopoldstr. 13</addr-line>
        <city>D-80802 Munich</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
        <postal-code>80802</postal-code>
      </aff>
      <aff id="aff-3-nb-article">
        <institution content-type="dept">Department of Psychology</institution>
        <institution-wrap>
          <institution>University of Graz</institution>
        </institution-wrap>
        <city>Graz</city>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </aff>
      <aff id="aff-4-nb-article">
        <institution-wrap>
          <institution>Charlotte Fresenius University of Psychology</institution>
        </institution-wrap>
        <city>Munich</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </aff>
      <aff id="regen-nb-article">
        <institution content-type="dept">Faculty of Psychology</institution>
        <institution-wrap>
          <institution>University of Regensburg</institution>
        </institution-wrap>
        <city>Regensburg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </aff>
      <author-notes>
        <corresp id="cor-2-nb-article">buehner@lmu.de</corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <abstract>
This article investigates whether gold-standard items are helpful for
questionnaire construction. Based on cognitive interviews
(<inline-formula><alternatives><tex-math><![CDATA[N]]></tex-math><mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"><mml:mi>N</mml:mi></mml:math></alternatives></inline-formula>
= 8) and a pilot study (<inline-formula><alternatives><tex-math><![CDATA[N]]></tex-math><mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"><mml:mi>N</mml:mi></mml:math></alternatives></inline-formula>
= 390) with an initial item set, three 12-item scales were constructed
to measure the physical traits of body height, body weight, and age. We
collected data on these scales using response formats with either two
(<inline-formula><alternatives><tex-math><![CDATA[N]]></tex-math><mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"><mml:mi>N</mml:mi></mml:math></alternatives></inline-formula>
= 921) or six (<inline-formula><alternatives><tex-math><![CDATA[N]]></tex-math><mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"><mml:mi>N</mml:mi></mml:math></alternatives></inline-formula>
= 933) categories. We also collected numeric self-reports of body
weight, body height, and age as gold-standard items. Confirmatory factor
analyses revealed that the gold-standard items did not consistently
exhibit the highest loading on their corresponding latent variable.
Furthermore, when controlling for the self-reported physical body
height, body weight, and age as gold-standard items, as well as gender,
we did not always find an interpretable, systematic residual variance.
Finally, the pattern of correlations between the latent variables did
not reflect the correlations between the self-reported gold-standard
items, suggesting that the item scales and the gold-standard items do
not have the same validity. While these results are consistent with
previous studies, our analyses also showed that items with two response
categories were at least as valid as those with six categories,
contradicting past recommendations. When constructing a questionnaire,
we would argue that the items intended to measure the latent variable
most directly should have the highest loading on that variable. If this
is not the case, the content validity is questionable at best. The
implications are that intensive cognitive pretesting is necessary.
Questionnaires with different response formats should be compared
empirically and hypotheses about which items best represent the latent
variable should be tested.
</abstract>
    </front-stub>
    <body>
      <sec specific-use="notebook-content">
        <code language="r script"># load datasets and results objects
# place chunk before the yaml header, so sample sizes can be reported in the abstract
library(papaja)</code>
        <boxed-text>
          <preformat>Loading required package: tinylabels</preformat>
        </boxed-text>
        <code language="r script">library(flextable)</code>
        <boxed-text>
          <preformat>
Attaching package: 'flextable'</preformat>
        </boxed-text>
        <boxed-text>
          <preformat>The following object is masked from 'package:papaja':

    theme_apa</preformat>
        </boxed-text>
        <code language="r script">library(tidyverse)</code>
        <boxed-text>
          <preformat>── Attaching core tidyverse packages ──────────────────────── tidyverse 2.0.0 ──
✔ dplyr     1.1.4     ✔ readr     2.1.5
✔ forcats   1.0.0     ✔ stringr   1.5.1
✔ ggplot2   3.5.2     ✔ tibble    3.3.0
✔ lubridate 1.9.4     ✔ tidyr     1.3.1
✔ purrr     1.1.0     </preformat>
        </boxed-text>
        <boxed-text>
          <preformat>── Conflicts ────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse_conflicts() ──
✖ purrr::compose() masks flextable::compose()
✖ dplyr::filter()  masks stats::filter()
✖ dplyr::lag()     masks stats::lag()
ℹ Use the conflicted package (&lt;http://conflicted.r-lib.org/&gt;) to force all conflicts to become errors</preformat>
        </boxed-text>
        <code language="r script">library(foreign)
dat_poly &lt;- read.spss("data/Haupterhebung Studie III (Polytom 6PS).sav", 
  to.data.frame = TRUE, use.value.labels = FALSE, na.omit = FALSE)
dat_dich &lt;- read.spss("data/Haupterhebung Studie III (Dichotom 2PS).sav",
  to.data.frame = TRUE, use.value.labels = FALSE, na.omit = FALSE)
dat_desc &lt;- bind_rows(
  dat_poly |&gt; select(Geschlecht, Bildung, Muttersprache, Alter_realW) |&gt; mutate(categories = "6 categories"),
  dat_dich |&gt; select(Geschlecht, Bildung, Muttersprache, Alter_realW) |&gt; mutate(categories = "2 categories"))
dat_interviews &lt;- read.spss("data/Stichprobe kognitive Interviews.sav", 
  to.data.frame = TRUE, use.value.labels = FALSE, na.omit = FALSE)
dat_pilot &lt;- read.spss("data/Pilottest_Studie_3.sav", 
  to.data.frame = TRUE, use.value.labels = FALSE, na.omit = FALSE)

results &lt;- readRDS("results/results.rds")
results_secondary &lt;- readRDS("results/results_secondary.rds")

papaja::r_refs(file = "r-references.bib")</code>
      </sec>
      <p>
</p>
      <p>Psychological researchers typically develop questionnaires and use
latent variable modeling to test whether they measure the intended
psychological construct
(<xref alt="Holt et al., 2010" rid="ref-tenholtScaleConstructionEvaluation2010-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Holt
et al., 2010</xref>). According to the most applied test models (e.g.,
factor analytic models) especially item discrimination parameters are
interpreted as how well items correlate with the latent variable (see
<xref alt="Lord et al., 1968" rid="ref-lordStatisticalTheoriesMental1968-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Lord
et al., 1968</xref>). Highly correlated items with the latent variable
indicate that these items are more important to measure the latent
variable compared to items with lower correlations. Thus, the item
discrimination parameter is typically used to assess the quality of an
item measuring the latent variable.</p>
      <p>To assure that we obtain high item discrimination parameters it is
essential to start with a precise definition of the latent variable. The
definition is the starting point for deriving items with content
validity. The item construction is believed to be theoretically sound if
items are selected from a larger population of possible indicators of
the latent variable in a representative manner to achieve high content
validity and ensure that we measure the indented construct. Let us
assume that we try to measure the latent variable <italic>interpersonal
warmth</italic> with the following adjectives:
<italic>affectionate</italic>, <italic>friendly</italic>,
<italic>talkative</italic>, <italic>unprejudiced</italic>. We ask how
well each adjective describes yourself from <italic>not at all</italic>
(0) to <italic>fully and entirely</italic> (4) with five response
categories. If these items measure warmth, they should at least all
significantly correlate with the adjective warmth measured with the same
response format. Even more, the warmth item should have the highest
discrimination parameter conducting a factor analysis with empirical
data, otherwise a different construct is measured, e.g., friendliness,
in the case that the adjective <italic>friendly</italic> has the highest
loading on the latent variable. This can be seen as a robustness check
that the latent variable has the intended meaning. In the following
sections, we refer to such items as <italic>gold-standard
items</italic>.</p>
      <p>In this study, we construct scales for the “physical traits”
<italic>body height</italic>, <italic>body weight</italic>, and
<italic>age</italic> and compare them with a gold-standard item, that
is, the numerical self-report of the respective physical property. We
derive three assumptions that should hold if a valid measurement of the
mentioned latent variables is possible. We base these assumptions on the
relevant literature on previous studies, item wording, and response
categories, which we will outline in the next section.</p>
      <sec id="theoretical-background-nb-article">
        <title>Theoretical Background</title>
        <sec id="evidence-using-gold-standard-items-nb-article">
          <title>Evidence Using Gold-Standard Items</title>
          <p>To demonstrate the validity of psychological measurements and the
    practical utility of psychological measurement models, Bortolotti et
    al.
    (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>)
    compared psychological measurement with physical measurement. They
    constructed a scale with 27 items intended to assess body height.
    Using a response format with two response categories, participants
    were asked to respond to items such as “Do I think, I would do well
    in a basketball team?”
    (<xref alt="Bortolotti et al., 2013, p. 2350" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Bortolotti
    et al., 2013, p. 2350</xref>). At the end of the scale, participants
    were asked to report their actual height in centimeters, the
    self-reported physical gold-standard item. The parameters estimated
    from the latent variable body height were then compared with the
    physical, gold-standard measurements. The results revealed a strong
    correlation (.86, not corrected for disattenuation) between the
    estimated person parameters derived from a two-parameter logistic
    model and the self-reported physical height. Still, the
    gold-standard item did not exhibit the highest loading on the scale
    (<xref alt="Bortolotti et al., 2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Bortolotti
    et al., 2013</xref>). Van der Linden
    (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-vanderlindenUnidimensionalLogisticResponse2016-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>)
    also employed a height measurement based on items with two response
    categories (e.g., “I bump my head quite often.”, p. 27) to
    illustrate the usefulness of logistic item response models.
    According to the author, this approach is unusual, as body height
    appears to be a physical variable that can only be measured using a
    yardstick. However, differences in height influence behavior, making
    it quite plausible to view such behavioral indicators as proxies for
    body height and to derive a psychological measurement from them. The
    two examples suggest that, first, gold-standard items do not always
    have the highest loading on the latent variable. Second, measuring a
    “physical” latent variable might be a psychological representation
    of body height rather than a measure of physical body height.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="item-wording-nb-article">
          <title>Item Wording</title>
          <p>One important aspect of item construction is item wording. In
    this context, Pargent et al.
    (<xref alt="2019" rid="ref-pargentCanMakeIt2019-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>)
    showed that the quality of item wording did, in fact, not impact
    model fit based on commonly used fit indices of confirmatory factor
    analyses. Sound item wording may not be crucial for achieving good
    model fit, but it clearly is for understanding the item correctly:
    For example, if a person does not correctly recognize an item with
    negative polarity, the person’s value on the scale is immediately
    over- or underestimated by a few points. In some cases, this can
    lead to considerable distortions in the test score. If a person does
    not understand the items correctly, their response cannot be valid,
    regardless of any model fit indicators (for an extreme example, see
    <xref alt="Maul, 2017" rid="ref-maulRethinking2017-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Maul,
    2017</xref>). Thus, it would be problematic to evaluate the quality
    of a questionnaire by solely looking at the model fit of the latent
    variable model, the discrimination parameters and/or reliability
    estimates. In this context, McNeish et al.
    (<xref alt="2018" rid="ref-mcneishThornyRelationMeasurement2018-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>)
    stated that good fit indices (e.g., Root Mean Square Error of
    Approximation, RMSEA; Standardized Root Mean Square Residual, SRMR;
    and the Comparative Fit Index, CFI) must be considered together with
    measurement quality (reliability) and the size of standardized
    factor loadings. They showed examples where all fit indices were
    excellent, but the standardized item loadings were .40, and another
    model where the fit indices were inadequate, but the factor loadings
    were .90. Thus, fit indices can be misleading without considering
    the quality of measurement.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="response-scale-nb-article">
          <title>Response Scale</title>
          <p>Hilbert et al.
    (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-hilbertInfluenceResponseFormat2016-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>)
    presented initial evidence that different response scales might not
    measure the same latent variable. They found that the correlation
    (disattenuated for measurement error) between latent variables
    measured by identical items ranged only from .76 to .88 when using
    items with two versus five response categories and a visual analogue
    scale. The question arises: Which of these questionnaires measures
    the true construct? What is well known is how the number of response
    categories affects reliability estimates. A vast amount of
    literature compares different numbers of response categories for
    rating scale items. We quote some exemplary studies to demonstrate
    how complex and difficult it is to choose a reasonable number of
    response categories and highlight what we can conclude from their
    results. Preston &amp; Colman
    (<xref alt="2000" rid="ref-prestonOptimalNumberResponse2000-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2000</xref>)
    reported that two response categories exhibited the lowest
    retest-reliability and a relatively poor validity and discriminating
    power. They recommend applying rating scales with at least seven
    response categories. In contrast, Lee &amp; Paek
    (<xref alt="2014, p. 663" rid="ref-leeSearchOptimalNumber2014-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2014,
    p. 663</xref>) concluded that “caution should be made if a scale has
    only two response categories, but that limitation may be overcome by
    manipulating other scale features, namely, scale length or item
    discrimination”. Weijters et al.
    (<xref alt="2010" rid="ref-weijtersEffectRatingScale2010-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>)
    recommend rating scales with five fully labeled response categories
    for samples drawn from the general population. In their
    recommendations, the authors considered an extreme response style,
    responses to reversed items, and an acquiescence response style.
    However, Masuda et al.
    (<xref alt="2017" rid="ref-masudaRespondentsLowMotivation2017-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>)
    found that low-motivated persons tend to use the middle category,
    implying that a middle category is not advisable. Similarly, Bradley
    et al.
    (<xref alt="2015, p. 8" rid="ref-bradleyRatingScalesSurvey2015-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2015,
    p. 8</xref>) concluded from their study that “for constructing
    measures from survey responses, the inclusion of a neutral middle
    category distorts the data to the point where it is not possible to
    construct meaningful measures.” All in all, the reviewed literature
    suggests that to achieve high reliability, seven response categories
    seem the be useful, but there is also evidence to omit the middle
    category due to the inconsistent use of it. Thus, we infer that
    there is evidence to use rating scales with six response categories
    without a middle category.</p>
        </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="implications-nb-article">
        <title>Implications</title>
        <p>We quote from a review on the application of Item Response Theory
  (IRT) models and factor analyses
  (<xref alt="Holt et al., 2010, p. 288" rid="ref-tenholtScaleConstructionEvaluation2010-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Holt
  et al., 2010, p. 288</xref>): “In our opinion, researchers could take
  far better advantage of their theoretical knowledge and/or
  expectations by incorporating their a priori knowledge of the items
  and scales in the analyses. This should be reflected 1) by a more
  frequent application of confirmatory techniques, especially in the
  construction of new scales and 2) by adding interpretability of
  factors and content of items to the criteria used for model
  evaluation.” Building on this summary statement, the aforementioned
  research and recommendations, we assess three physical “traits” to
  replicate and extend previous findings. First, we constructed scales
  for body height, body weight, and age. Second, we used items with two
  response categories to replicate the results of Bortolotti et al.
  (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>)
  for body height. Third, we applied an additional format containing six
  response categories without a middle category which low-motivated
  persons tend to overuse (e.g., see
  <xref alt="Masuda et al., 2017" rid="ref-masudaRespondentsLowMotivation2017-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Masuda
  et al., 2017</xref>). We aimed to investigate whether 1) the results
  of Bortolotti et al.
  (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>)
  hold true for body height and similar physical traits, and whether 2)
  there really is a psychological component in self-report
  questionnaires of physical traits as assumed by Van der Linden
  (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-vanderlindenUnidimensionalLogisticResponse2016-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>).
  Furthermore, we assumed that items with six response categories have
  higher reliability and thus, higher loadings and better validity than
  those with two response categories
  (<xref alt="Lee &amp; Paek, 2014" rid="ref-leeSearchOptimalNumber2014-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Lee
  &amp; Paek, 2014</xref>;
  <xref alt="Preston &amp; Colman, 2000" rid="ref-prestonOptimalNumberResponse2000-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Preston
  &amp; Colman, 2000</xref>;
  <xref alt="Weijters et al., 2010" rid="ref-weijtersEffectRatingScale2010-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Weijters
  et al., 2010</xref>). The concrete assumptions underlying our research
  are the following:<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1-nb-article">1</xref></p>
        <list list-type="bullet">
          <list-item>
            <p><italic>Assumption 1:</italic> From a theoretical point of
      view, the self-reported physical body height, body weight, and age
      as the self-reported gold-standard items should have the highest
      factor loading (which is equivalent to a high correlation between
      the latent variable and the item applying a one-factor model)
      compared to other questionnaire items measuring the respective
      physical trait.</p>
          </list-item>
          <list-item>
            <p><italic>Assumption 2:</italic> The measurement of physical
      traits with questionnaire items should have a psychological
      component because the self-reported physical measurement and
      gender (as there are gender differences in perception, see
      <xref alt="McCreary, 2002" rid="ref-mccrearyGenderAgeDifferences2002-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">McCreary,
      2002</xref>) cannot fully explain the item responses. Systematic
      correlated residuals should remain.</p>
          </list-item>
          <list-item>
            <p><italic>Assumption 3a, b:</italic> The correlational pattern
      between the latent variables for the physical traits should
      correspond to the correlation of the self-reported gold-standard
      items (3a) and the factor loadings and reliability estimates
      should be higher for scales with 6-point response categories
      compared to 2-point response categories (3b).</p>
          </list-item>
        </list>
        <p>
  </p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="methods-nb-article">
        <title>Methods</title>
        <p>All materials (reproducible manuscript, analysis code, datasets,
  codebooks, questionnaires) for this manuscript are openly available on
  the Open Science Framework (OSF) at
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://osf.io/p7492/">https://osf.io/p7492/</ext-link>.
  A Quarto Manuscripts website presenting the manuscript and electronic
  supplementary materials is hosted at
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://florianpargent.github.io/gold-standard-items/">https://florianpargent.github.io/gold-standard-items/</ext-link>.</p>
        <sec id="item-construction-nb-article">
          <title>Item Construction</title>
          <p>First, we constructed items for the physical characteristics of
    body height, body weight, and age. Age was defined as chronological
    age or age in years, corresponding to the time elapsed since a
    person’s birth
    (<xref alt="Montepare &amp; Lachman, 1989" rid="ref-montepareYouReOnly1989-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Montepare
    &amp; Lachman, 1989</xref>;
    <xref alt="Schwall, 2012" rid="ref-schwallDefiningAgeUsing2012-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Schwall,
    2012</xref>). Height was defined as the height of an upright person
    from the sole of the foot to the top of the head in centimeters, and
    body weight as the physical mass of a person in kilograms
    (<xref alt="Martin, 1929" rid="ref-martinAnthropometrieAnleitungSelbstaendigen1929-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Martin,
    1929</xref>). The initial items were developed by 124 psychology
    students (deductive item construction,
    <xref alt="Burisch, 1984" rid="ref-burischApproachesPersonalityInventory1984-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Burisch,
    1984</xref>) and 24 persons (prototype approach, see
    <xref alt="Broughton, 1984" rid="ref-broughtonPrototypeStrategyConstruction1984-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Broughton,
    1984</xref>) who deviated from the German population mean at least
    one standard deviation in the relevant characteristics (separately
    for women and men). The 24 persons were asked to think of
    prototypical behaviors for each construct to assess the whole
    spectrum of the latent variable. This process resulted in an initial
    set of 138 items (response categories were not tested). In a second
    step, we examined how these items were interpreted and whether they
    were connected to additional concepts unrelated to the constructs
    using cognitive interviews. We conducted interviews with a length of
    two to three hours and applied various cognitive procedures,
    including probing, paraphrasing, concurrent-think-aloud, and
    retrospective-think-aloud
    (<xref alt="Prüfer &amp; Rexroth, 1996" rid="ref-prueferVerfahrenEvaluationSurvey1996-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Prüfer
    &amp; Rexroth, 1996</xref>,
    <xref alt="2005" rid="ref-prueferKognitiveInterviews2005-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>).
    The literature on cognitive interviews recommends five to 30
    interviews but indicates that the most serious problems can already
    be identified with a small number of interviews
    (<xref alt="Willis, 2005" rid="ref-willisCognitiveInterviewing2005-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Willis,
    2005</xref>). The interviews were conducted with 8 people from the
    target group (4 women and 4 men) aged between 21 and 77
    (<italic>M</italic> = 44.50, <italic>SD</italic> = 20.78). The level
    of education ranged from high school diploma to university degree.
    After the cognitive interviews, misleading items were reformulated
    or eliminated
    (<xref alt="Faulbaum et al., 2009" rid="ref-faulbaumWasIstGute2009-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Faulbaum
    et al., 2009</xref>), resulting in 61 remaining items. In a third
    step, these 61 items were pilot tested online on a new sample, which
    initially consisted of 456 people. However, we excluded 66 subjects
    because they had not completed the questionnaire, resulting in a
    sample of 390 participants aged between 18 and 77 years
    (<italic>M</italic> = 31.91, <italic>SD</italic> = 12.82), including
    302 women (77.44 %) and 88 men (22.56 %). The level of education was
    distributed as follows: 0 % no school leaving certificate, 3.33 %
    secondary school leaving certificate/elementary school or
    equivalent, 17.18 % secondary school or equivalent, 35.90 %
    vocational baccalaureate or high school diploma, 40.77 % college
    degree or university degree, 2.82 % doctorate or habilitation. Out
    of all respondents, 95.38 % stated German as their native language.
    Based on these survey responses, we excluded items if a) their main
    item loading was not on the intended factor, b) their main and
    secondary loadings were almost equal, or c) they had loading below
    or equal to .30. Additionally, if (d) items had very similar
    content, items with lower loadings were excluded. More details on
    the process of item construction can be found in Eichhorn
    (<xref alt="2019" rid="ref-eichhornItem2019-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>).
    We reproduced the exploratory factor analyses, item total
    correlations and reliability estimates that were computed in the
    final item selection stage and report them in our electronic
    supplementary materials. Based on these criteria 12 final items were
    selected for each physical trait (see
    <xref alt="Table 5" rid="tbl-5-nb-article">Table 5</xref>).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn2-nb-article">2</xref>
    For each of the three questionnaires, two versions were created –
    one with a 6-point scale combining verbal endpoints (“does not
    apply” to “applies”, only endpoints were labeled) with full numeric
    anchoring (numbers from 1 to 6) and one with a 2-point scale
    combining verbal labels (“does not apply” and “applies”) with
    numeric anchors (numbers 0 and 1).</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="statistical-analysis-nb-article">
          <title>Statistical Analysis</title>
          <p>All analyses were conducted in R version 4.5.1 (2025-06-13). A
    full list of software versions can be found in
    (<xref alt="apx-3?" rid="ref-apx-3-nb-article" ref-type="bibr"><bold>apx-3?</bold></xref>).
    The data were analyzed using confirmatory factor analyses using the
    package <italic>lavaan</italic>
    (<xref alt="Rosseel, 2012" rid="ref-R-lavaan-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Rosseel,
    2012</xref>). We used the weighted least squares, mean and variance
    adjusted (WLSMV) estimator, treating the questionnaire items as
    ordinal and the self-reported physical gold-standard items body
    height, body weight, and age as continuous variables. First, we
    specified (1) unidimensional models without any error correlations,
    and (2) models with one latent variable and correlated errors. In
    both models the gold-standard items and the other 12 items were
    specified as indicators of a single latent variable. Second, to test
    whether there is a latent variable while controlling for the
    gold-standard item and gender, (3) models were specified with a
    single latent variable where the questionnaire items were
    additionally predicted by the gold-standard item and gender. Third,
    to compare the correlations between the latent variables with the
    correlations between the gold-standard items, (4) full three factor
    models without correlated errors were estimated, in which only the
    questionnaire items load on their respective latent variable and
    correlations are estimated between the latent variables, between the
    gold-standard items, and between the latent variables and the
    gold-standard items. We also conducted reliability analyses using
    the package <italic>MBESS</italic>
    (<xref alt="Kelley, 2023" rid="ref-R-MBESS-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Kelley,
    2023</xref>) and report McDonald’s Omega as a reliability estimate
    of internal consistency for each scale.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="sample-nb-article">
          <title>Sample</title>
          <p>The total sample of our main study consisted of 1854 participants
    aged between 18 and 97 years (<italic>M</italic> = 32.70,
    <italic>SD</italic> = 16.01), including 1036 women (56%) and 818 men
    (44%). The overall sample consisted of two independent subsamples,
    which were divided into the 2-point and 6-point response format
    conditions.</p>
          <p>Participants were recruited in trains, colleges, universities,
    adult education centers, fitness studios and various public places
    in Germany and Austria in November and December 2017. Participation
    was voluntary and without reimbursement. Each participant was handed
    a paper and pencil questionnaire, alternating between the 2-point
    and 6-point response scale versions. When a participant handed back
    the questionnaire, the facilitator immediately checked for missing
    values, in which case the participant was politely asked to complete
    the missing questions. With this procedure, we achieved complete
    responses for all questionnaires.</p>
          <p><xref alt="Table 1" rid="tbl-1-nb-article">Table 1</xref> shows the
    distribution of gender, level of education, native language, and age
    within the two conditions. As expected based on the randomization
    procedure, the two subsamples are very similar. Due to the
    left-skewed age distribution and outlier values, the median is
    reported as a measure of the central tendency instead of the
    mean.</p>
          <sec specific-use="notebook-content">
            <code language="r script">results$table1</code>
            <fig id="tbl-1-nb-article">
              <caption>
                <p>Table 1: Sample characteristics within response
      category conditions</p>
              </caption>
              <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="manuscript_files/figure-jats/tbl-1-1.png"/>
            </fig>
          </sec>
          <p>
    </p>
        </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="results-nb-article">
        <title>Results</title>
        <sec id="assumption-1-the-self-reported-physical-body-height-weight-and-age-should-have-the-highest-loadings-on-their-latent-variables.-nb-article">
          <title><italic>Assumption 1:</italic> The self-reported physical
    body height, weight, and age should have the highest loadings on
    their latent variables.</title>
          <p><xref alt="Table 2" rid="tbl-2-nb-article">Table 2</xref> displays the
    measurement models for the three scales for body height, body
    weight, and age for two and six response categories each.</p>
          <sec specific-use="notebook-content">
            <code language="r script">results$table2</code>
            <fig id="tbl-2-nb-article">
              <caption>
                <p>Table 2: Standardized item loadings (correlations with
      the latent variable) for two and six response
      categories</p>
              </caption>
              <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="manuscript_files/figure-jats/tbl-2-1.png"/>
            </fig>
          </sec>
          <p>
    </p>
          <p>Overall, both response formats produced similar loading patterns,
    but those with two response categories obtained slightly higher
    loadings compared to six response categories for most items.
    Questionnaires with two response categories showed slightly better
    fit indices than those with six categories. All model fits were
    within the expected range for psychological questionnaires
    (<xref alt="Goretzko et al., 2024" rid="ref-goretzkoEvaluatingModelFit2024-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Goretzko
    et al., 2024</xref>). In particular, the fit indices for the
    questionnaires on body height and weight with two response
    categories showed the best fit.</p>
          <sec specific-use="notebook-content">
            <code language="r script">higher_load &lt;- results$load_df_nomod |&gt; group_by(measure, categories) |&gt;
  reframe(freq = sum(head(abs(est.std), 12) &gt; tail(abs(est.std), 1)))</code>
          </sec>
          <p>For the body height scales, the self-reported physical height
    loaded higher or similarly high on the latent variables compared to
    the questionnaire items. However, this pattern slightly differed for
    the weight and age scales, where several items loaded substantially
    higher on the latent variable than the physical items: For weight,
    the items 4 (“I am obese.”) and 5 (“I weigh a lot.”) had especially
    high loadings on the latent variable for the questionnaires with two
    and six response categories. For age, item 7 (“I have already lived
    most of my life.”) had especially high loadings on the latent
    variable for the questionnaires with two and six response
    categories. The item loadings for the weight and age scales suggest
    that the gold-standard items were not essential for measuring the
    latent variable.</p>
          <sec specific-use="notebook-content">
            <code language="r script"># correlation of loadings between cfa models with and without correlated errors
r_loadings &lt;- cor.test(
  # use absolute values because the items were not recoded for cfa models
  abs(results$load_df_nomod$est.std), abs(results_secondary$load_df_mod$est.std), 
  method = "pearson")
r_loadings &lt;- apa_print(r_loadings)$table</code>
          </sec>
          <p>Even after allowing for correlated errors as suggested by
    standard modification indices, the loading patterns did not improve
    (see <xref alt="Table 5" rid="tbl-5-nb-article">Table 5</xref>). Loading
    patterns with and without modifications were correlated at .98
    (<italic>p</italic> &lt; .001) across all questionnaires (body
    height, body weight, age) and response variants (two and six
    categories).</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="assumption-2-the-measurement-should-have-a-psychological-component-and-the-item-responses-cannot-be-fully-explained-by-the-self-reported-physical-measurement-and-gender.-a-systemic-residual-should-remain-when-corrected-for-self-reported-physical-height-and-gender.-nb-article">
          <title><italic>Assumption 2:</italic> The measurement should have a
    psychological component, and the item responses cannot be fully
    explained by the self-reported physical measurement and gender. A
    systemic residual should remain when corrected for self-reported
    physical height and gender.</title>
          <p><xref alt="Table 3" rid="tbl-3-nb-article">Table 3</xref> displays item
    loadings on the latent variable when controlling for the
    self-reported physical item and self-reported gender.</p>
          <sec specific-use="notebook-content">
            <code language="r script">results$table3</code>
            <fig id="tbl-3-nb-article">
              <caption>
                <p>Table 3: Standardized item loadings on the latent
      variable for two and six categories controlling for the
      self-reported physical item and self-reported gender</p>
              </caption>
              <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="manuscript_files/figure-jats/tbl-3-1.png"/>
            </fig>
          </sec>
          <p>
    </p>
          <p>For body height, we obtained low item loadings on the latent
    variable but high regression weights with the gold-standard item of
    physical body height. In particular, the third item (“Chairs and
    tables are usually too low for me.”) exhibited the highest loading
    on the latent variable for both response formats. In contrast, item
    11 (“I have to stand at the front of group photos so that I can be
    seen clearly.”) and item 12 (“When I hug other people in greeting, I
    have to bend downwards.”) were best predicted by the self-reported
    physical body height for both response
    formats.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn3-nb-article">3</xref> This pattern does not
    convincingly confirm the existence of a psychological latent height
    variable after controlling for the self-reported physical item and
    gender.</p>
          <p>For body weight, the items with high loadings on the latent
    variable also exhibited high associations with the self-reported
    physical body weight. Item 4 (“I am obese.”) had the highest loading
    on the latent variable for both response formats. Item 5 (“I weigh a
    lot.”) was explained best by the self-reported physical body weight.
    Item 9 (“I have a lot of space between the armrests in airplane
    seats.”) had a low loading on the latent variable but was moderately
    predicted by the self-reported physical body weight for both
    response formats. Notably, item 11 (“If I have the choice between
    the elevator and the stairs, I take the elevator.”) was not related
    to either the self-reported physical item or the latent variable for
    both response formats, indicating that it may represent a more
    health-related perspective. Taken together, the resulting latent
    weight variable is hard to interpret.</p>
          <p>For age, we observed the biggest discrepancy between items with
    high loadings on the latent variable and items best predicted by
    self-reported physical age. Item 3 (“I have a lot of life
    experience.”) and item 9 (“I have years of work experience.”) did
    not load on the latent variable after controlling for physical age
    and gender but were predicted by self-reported physical age for both
    response formats. In contrast, the three items most prototypical of
    the latent variable were item 2 (“Over time, my mental capacity has
    decreased.”), item 5 (“Over time, my memory has deteriorated.”), and
    item 4 (“Over time, my ability to react has decreased.”) for both
    response formats. Thus, the latent variable might be interpreted as
    mental age, but not all items have a substantial loading on this
    general factor.</p>
          <p>When looking at self-reported gender, there are moderate
    standardized regression weights for some items of body height (e.g.,
    item 8 “Pants are often so short for me.”) and body weight (e.g.,
    item 6 “I need to lose weight.”). These items may cause problems
    when applied to both men and women (differential item functioning;
    see
    <xref alt="Hilbert et al., 2022" rid="ref-hilbertWhatMeasureEmpirical2022-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Hilbert
    et al., 2022</xref>, for a comparable case). Notably, there are only
    non-significant low standardized regression weights of self-reported
    gender predicting age items.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="assumption-3a-b-the-correlational-pattern-between-the-latent-variables-for-the-construct-should-correspond-to-the-correlations-of-the-self-reported-gold-standard-items-and-the-validity-should-be-higher-for-the-6-point-response-categories-compared-to-the-2-point-response-categories.-nb-article">
          <title>Assumption 3a, b: The correlational pattern between the
    latent variables for the construct should correspond to the
    correlations of the self-reported gold-standard items and the
    validity should be higher for the 6-point response categories
    compared to the 2-point response categories.</title>
          <p>As depicted in <xref alt="Table 4" rid="tbl-4-nb-article">Table 4</xref>,
    the correlations between the latent variables do not match those
    between the self-reported physical items. While height and age
    showed relatively similar low correlations, the physical
    correlations of weight and age were overestimated by the
    correlations between the latent variables and the physical
    correlations between height and weight were underestimated. Most
    notably, correlations did not differ substantially between the
    questionnaires with two and with six response categories.
    Descriptively, the physical correlations seemed to be reproduced by
    the latent correlations slightly better for the two response
    categories. However, reliability estimates (Omega) were lower for
    two response categories compared to six response categories.</p>
          <sec specific-use="notebook-content">
            <code language="r script">results$table4</code>
            <fig id="tbl-4-nb-article">
              <caption>
                <p>Table 4: Correlations between the latent variables
      body height, body weight and age, reliability estimates, and
      correlations between the corresponding self-reported physical
      items for two and six response categories</p>
              </caption>
              <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="manuscript_files/figure-jats/tbl-4-1.png"/>
            </fig>
          </sec>
          <p>
    </p>
        </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="discussion-nb-article">
        <title>Discussion</title>
        <sec id="summary-nb-article">
          <title>Summary</title>
          <p>The goal of this study was to find out whether gold-standard
    items have the highest loadings on the corresponding latent
    variable. This was investigated using items with two and six
    response categories which measure these physical traits. The results
    reveal that this is only an exception, and two response categories
    perform not necessarily worse than six response categories regarding
    validity and reliability. Gold-standard items might help to ensure
    the interpretation of the latent variable. The choice of the
    response format should be based on empirical testing and extensive
    cognitive interviews. It seems not sufficient to take advice from
    the literature on how to choose the number of response categories to
    optimize reliability. The benefit of gold-standard items will be
    discussed in the following sections.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="gold-standard-items-nb-article">
          <title>Gold-Standard Items</title>
          <p>Gold-standard items did not work as theoretically expected in
    this study. However, we still believe they are important. Only the
    gold-standard item for body height – for six, not for two response
    categories – had the highest loading on the latent variable.
    Bortolotti et al.
    (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>),
    who previously applied the same procedure with two response
    categories to investigate a gold-standard item for body height,
    found a correlation of .86 with body height. This correlation pretty
    much matches our correlation with the latent variable. The
    correlation was slightly higher for our 2-response category scale
    (.87) compared to our 6-response category scale (.86), but there
    were also items which had descriptively equal or higher correlations
    (biserial correlations) with the sum score than the self-reported
    physical item (Pearson correlation). This might be because we
    reported a latent correlation corrected for disattenuation, and our
    scale had 12 instead of 27 items. Nevertheless, our results depict a
    conceptual replication of Bortolotti et al.
    (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>)
    with a different questionnaire.</p>
          <p>The results differed for the other latent variables of body
    weight and age, which exhibited lower correlations between the
    latent variable and their gold-standard items. This seems
    problematic as these items were designed to be the “gold” measure of
    the latent variable and should ensure a consistent interpretation.
    Thus, we should carefully reflect what this finding means for item
    construction for psychological scales of non-physical traits. If
    this basic requirement is not met, even for traits that seem rather
    straightforward to measure, what about more complex constructs? To
    avoid a misleading interpretation of a latent variable, it might be
    very helpful to formulate a priori hypotheses about the importance
    of the constructed items as we did here to test the construct
    validity of a test. If we, for example, want to measure
    <italic>interpersonal warmth</italic> as a big five facet and
    construct items that describe this facet, an item that most directly
    measures warmth should have its highest loading on the latent
    variable, otherwise the interpretation of the latent variable is not
    justified.</p>
          <p>We must be aware, that general model fit does not prove how well
    items are formulated (see
    <xref alt="Pargent et al., 2019" rid="ref-pargentCanMakeIt2019-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Pargent
    et al., 2019</xref>). Model fit also does not reveal if the applied
    items are helpful to measure the latent variable. Model fit simply
    compares a model implied variance/covariance matrix with an
    empirical variance/covariance matrix. In this study, the a priori
    most suitable items did not have always the highest discrimination
    parameters or loadings. Thus, simply selecting items according to
    their loadings and letting the factor analysis decide which item is
    good or not is probably insufficient. There must be an item content
    loading fit.</p>
          <p>The reliability estimate of the questionnaire informs us only
    about the precision of measurement and not whether our measurement
    is valid. This does not necessarily contradict attempts to choose
    items based on reliability (e.g., see
    <xref alt="Zijlmans et al., 2019" rid="ref-zijlmansItemScoreReliabilitySelection2019-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Zijlmans
    et al., 2019</xref>) since items must have high loadings to achieve
    high reliability estimates for the scale.</p>
          <p>Thus, we suggest using gold-standard items as described above. It
    should be noted, however, that it is critical not to implement the
    gold-standard item in the final scale since we would then create a
    part-whole relationship. This no desirable situation since all test
    models (classical and IRT models) assume that the probability of a
    positive response of a person to an item should not depend on this
    person’s response to any other item
    (<xref alt="Debelak &amp; Koller, 2020" rid="ref-debelakTestingLocalIndependence2020-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Debelak
    &amp; Koller, 2020</xref>).</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="physical-traits-as-psychological-variables-nb-article">
          <title>Physical Traits as Psychological Variables</title>
          <p>Previous hints suggest that measuring physical attributes through
    psychological questionnaires is not always connected to a
    psychological latent variable guiding behavior
    (<xref alt="Hilbert et al., 2022" rid="ref-hilbertWhatMeasureEmpirical2022-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Hilbert
    et al., 2022</xref>;
    <xref alt="Van der Linden, 2016" rid="ref-vanderlindenUnidimensionalLogisticResponse2016-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Van
    der Linden, 2016</xref>). Similarly, in our study, it remained
    unclear if a psychological latent variable beyond body height and
    weight was measured and how such a latent variable could be
    interpreted. Only for age there was a latent variable, which can be
    interpreted as cognitive or psychological age
    (<xref alt="Barak &amp; Schiffman, 1981" rid="ref-barakCognitiveAgeNonchronological1981-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Barak
    &amp; Schiffman, 1981</xref>). Furthermore, it seems helpful to
    include additional items, that are not intended to be measured but
    may further explain the item responses of interest, such as gender
    or items from the nomological net to reveal possible dependencies
    and to decide whether these dependencies are in line with the
    definition of the latent variables.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="number-of-categories-nb-article">
          <title>Number of Categories</title>
          <p>As expected, reliability estimates were higher for scales with
    six response categories compared to two categories. The results with
    regard to model fit and validity, indicated as correlations between
    latent variables compared to the correlation between gold-standard
    items, are mixed. Some fit indices suggested slightly better fit for
    items with two response categories and some for six categories. The
    same holds true for the differences between the correlations of the
    gold-standard items and the correlations of the latent variables.
    Except for reliability, the study revealed no clear picture to
    choose between two or six response categories. Hilbert et al.
    (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-hilbertInfluenceResponseFormat2016-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>,
    <xref alt="2022" rid="ref-hilbertWhatMeasureEmpirical2022-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2022</xref>)
    showed that the same items with a different number of response
    categories do not measure the same latent variable. This result
    highlights that the choice of the number of response categories
    constructing a questionnaire should be based on an empirical study
    comparing several options accompanied by an intensive cognitive
    pretesting phase and not only based on the literature which focuses
    on maximal reliability.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="recommendations-nb-article">
          <title>Recommendations</title>
          <p>The results presented here should prompt reflection and
    reconsideration of standard procedures of item construction in
    psychology. First, it may be helpful to more strongly consider
    content validity when developing items. Items that either represent
    a kind of gold-standard with specific hypotheses about the ranking
    of the loadings or construct-divergent items that (in)validate the
    items intended to measure a latent variable should be included in
    the construction process. Revisiting the example of
    <italic>interpersonal warmth</italic> as a personality facet, such
    additional validation items could, for example, measure warmth
    itself or openness. An openness scale or marker items that show high
    correlations with these warmth items should not be included in the
    final scale but only used for validation purposes. These demands are
    not entirely new, but should be newly emphasized based on the
    results of our analyses, calling for more stringent item
    construction approaches. Second, the choice of an optimal response
    scale may not be as clear-cut as previously suggested (e.g.,
    <xref alt="Lee &amp; Paek, 2014" rid="ref-leeSearchOptimalNumber2014-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Lee
    &amp; Paek, 2014</xref>). We found that items with two response
    categories were not per se unfavorable, as often suggested in the
    literature. While our binary scales obtained lower reliability
    estimates as expected (see
    <xref alt="Preston &amp; Colman, 2000" rid="ref-prestonOptimalNumberResponse2000-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Preston
    &amp; Colman, 2000</xref>;
    <xref alt="Revilla et al., 2014" rid="ref-revillaChoosingNumberCategories2014-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Revilla
    et al., 2014</xref>), other results regarding validity and model fit
    were mixed. Since reliability is easier to control for by adding
    more suitable items, construct validity seems to be the stronger
    argument when choosing the number of response categories. In sum, we
    believe that decisions on response scales should be empirically
    founded, especially in high stakes situations (e.g., clinical
    diagnosis or personnel selection), comparing alternative numbers of
    response categories in pilot testing. In this context, it is
    important to recognize that the number of response categories can
    influence what latent variables are measured (see
    <xref alt="Hilbert et al., 2016" rid="ref-hilbertInfluenceResponseFormat2016-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Hilbert
    et al., 2016</xref>,
    <xref alt="2022" rid="ref-hilbertWhatMeasureEmpirical2022-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2022</xref>).
    Thus, comparing the construct validity of questionnaires differing
    in the number of response categories is essential. Nevertheless, it
    remains necessary to subject response scales to intensive cognitive
    pretesting to determine a suitable number of categories. On the one
    hand, cognitive interviews can reveal when single categories are
    systematically overlooked by respondents lacking information or
    cognitive capacity to differentiate categories. On the other hand,
    cognitive pretests help assess participants’ cognitive load, which
    should always be kept in mind. For example, two-point scales, which
    are commonly criticized, have previously been shown to require less
    effort from the respondents
    (<xref alt="Hilbert et al., 2016" rid="ref-hilbertInfluenceResponseFormat2016-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Hilbert
    et al., 2016</xref>).</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="conclusion-nb-article">
          <title>Conclusion</title>
          <p>Based on the results of the present study, we advocate the
    inclusion of gold-standard items, i.e. items that are supposed to
    measure the intended construct most directly, to check the
    interpretation of latent variables in the construction of
    psychological questionnaires. In addition, for questionnaires that
    are used to make particularly important decisions, we recommend
    empirically testing the choice of response format, considering both
    validity and reliability to make a well-founded decision. The
    pre-selection of response formats should include cognitive pretests
    of the items.</p>
          <p>
    </p>
        </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="references-nb-article">
        <title>References</title>
      </sec>
      <sec id="apx-1-nb-article">
        <title>CFA models with correlated errors</title>
        <sec specific-use="notebook-content">
          <code language="r script">r_H10_H11_6 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "KGr_22" &amp; rhs == "KGr_23" &amp; categories == 6) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)
r_H10_H11_2 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "KGr_22" &amp; rhs == "KGr_23" &amp; categories == 2) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)

r_H4_H9_6 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "KGr_16" &amp; rhs == "KGr_21" &amp; categories == 6) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)
r_H4_H9_2 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "KGr_16" &amp; rhs == "KGr_21" &amp; categories == 2) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)

r_W6_W12_6 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "KGe_30" &amp; rhs == "KGe_36" &amp; categories == 6) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)
r_W6_W12_2 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "KGe_30" &amp; rhs == "KGe_36" &amp; categories == 2) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)

r_W3_W7_6 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "KGe_27" &amp; rhs == "KGe_31" &amp; categories == 6) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)
r_W3_W7_2 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "KGe_27" &amp; rhs == "KGe_31" &amp; categories == 2) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)

r_A3_A9_6 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "A_3" &amp; rhs == "A_9" &amp; categories == 6) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)
r_A3_A9_2 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "A_3" &amp; rhs == "A_9" &amp; categories == 2) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)

r_A2_A5_6 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "A_2" &amp; rhs == "A_5" &amp; categories == 6) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)
r_A2_A5_2 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "A_2" &amp; rhs == "A_5" &amp; categories == 2) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)

r_A7_A10_6 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "A_7" &amp; rhs == "A_10" &amp; categories == 6) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)
r_A7_A10_2 &lt;- results_secondary$cor_errors |&gt;
  filter(lhs == "A_7" &amp; rhs == "A_10" &amp; categories == 2) |&gt;
  pull(est.std)</code>
        </sec>
        <sec specific-use="notebook-content">
          <code language="r script">results_secondary$table5</code>
          <fig id="tbl-5-nb-article">
            <caption>
              <p>Table 5: Latent variable loadings for two and six
    response categories with correlated errors</p>
            </caption>
            <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="manuscript_files/figure-jats/tbl-5-1.png"/>
          </fig>
        </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="apx-2-nb-article">
        <title>Item translations</title>
        <p>
          <bold>Table B2</bold>
        </p>
        <p>Translated items used in this study</p>
        <table-wrap>
          <table>
            <colgroup>
              <col width="26%"/>
              <col width="74%"/>
            </colgroup>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th align="left">Item</th>
                <th align="left">Item wording (Original wording in
          German)</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 1</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I keep my head down when I walk through
          doors. (Ich ziehe den Kopf ein wenn ich durch Türen
          gehe.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 2</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">In the middle of a crowd, I can see over most
          other people. (Inmitten einer Menschenmenge kann ich über die
          meisten anderen Menschen hinwegblicken.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 3</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">Chairs and tables are usually too low for me.
          (Stühle und Tische sind meistens zu niedrig für mich.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 4</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">In the supermarket, I can reach the things on
          the top shelf without any problems. (Im Supermarkt komme ich
          ohne Probleme an die Sachen im obersten Regal.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 5</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">When I drive a car that was previously driven
          by someone else, I usually have to push the seat backwards.
          (Wenn ich ein Auto fahre, das vorher jemand anderes gefahren
          hat, muss ich üblicherweise den Sitz nach hinten
          schieben.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 6</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">When I stretch out straight in hotel beds, my
          feet overlap. (Wenn ich mich in Hotelbetten gerade ausstrecke,
          dann stehen meine Füße über.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 7</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">On airplanes, I bump my knees against the
          seat in front of me. (Im Flugzeug stoße ich mit den Knien am
          Vordersitz an.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 8</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">Pants are often too short for me. (Hosen sind
          mir häufig zu kurz.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 9</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I need a chair if I want to get things from
          the top shelf. (Ich brauche einen Stuhl, wenn ich Sachen aus
          dem obersten Regal holen möchte.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 10</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I have to look up when I talk to other
          people. (Wenn ich mich mit anderen Menschen unterhalte muss
          ich nach oben schauen.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 11</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I have to stand at the front of group photos
          so that I can be seen clearly. (Ich muss mich bei Gruppenfotos
          nach vorne stellen, damit ich gut zu sehen bin.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Height 12</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">When I hug other people in greeting, I have
          to bend downwards. (Wenn ich andere Menschen zur Begrüßung
          umarme, muss ich mich nach unten beugen.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 1</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I am often afraid that chairs will give way
          under me. (Ich habe oft Angst, dass Stühle unter mir
          nachgeben.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 2</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">Other people may think that I sit on the sofa
          in the evening and eat chocolate and potato chips.
          (Möglicherweise denken andere Menschen von mir, dass ich
          abends auf dem Sofa sitze und Schokolade und Chips esse.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 3</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I have a wide waistband when it comes to
          pants. (Bei Hosen habe ich eine große Bundweite.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 4</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I am obese. (Ich bin dick.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 5</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I weigh a lot. (Ich wiege viel.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 6</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I need to lose weight. (Ich müsste
          abnehmen.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 7</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">My pants have a small waistband. (Meine Hosen
          haben eine kleine Bundweite.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 8</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I am good at squeezing through narrow gaps.
          (Ich kann mich gut durch enge Spalten quetschen.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 9</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I have a lot of space between the armrests in
          airplane seats. (Zwischen den Armlehnen in Flugzeugsitzen habe
          ich viel Platz.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 10</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I take up a lot of space in the elevator. (Im
          Aufzug nehme ich viel Platz ein.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 11</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">If I have the choice between the elevator and
          the stairs, I take the elevator. (Wenn ich die Wahl habe
          zwischen Aufzug und Treppe, dann nehme ich den Aufzug.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Weight 12</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I should eat less. (Ich sollte weniger
          essen.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 1</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I have physical ailments. (Ich habe
          körperliche Gebrechen.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 2</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">Over time, my mental capacity has decreased.
          (Im Laufe der Zeit hat meine geistige Leistungsfähigkeit
          abgenommen.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 3</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I have a lot of life experience. (Ich habe
          viel Lebenserfahrung.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 4</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">Over time, my ability to react has decreased.
          (Im Laufe der Zeit hat meine Reaktionsfähigkeit
          abgenommen.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 5</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">Over time, my memory has deteriorated. (Im
          Laufe der Zeit hat meine Merkfähigkeit abgenommen.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 6</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I worry a lot about getting older. (Ich mache
          mir viele Gedanken über das Älterwerden.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 7</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I have already lived most of my life. (Den
          größten Teil meines Lebens habe ich bereits gelebt.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 8</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I find it increasingly difficult to follow
          technical developments. (Ich habe zunehmend Schwierigkeiten
          technischen Weiterentwicklungen zu folgen.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 9</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I have years of work experience. (Ich habe
          jahrelange Berufserfahrung.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 10</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">My whole life still lies ahead of me. (Mein
          ganzes Leben liegt noch vor mir.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 11</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I used to be more willing to take risks.
          (Früher war ich risikofreudiger.)</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td align="left">
                  <bold>Age 12</bold>
                </td>
                <td align="left">I carry out everyday activities more slowly
          than before. (Ich verrichte Alltagstätigkeiten langsamer als
          früher.)</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
        </table-wrap>
        <p><italic>Note:</italic> Original wording in German shown in
  parenthesis.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="apx-3-nb-article">
        <title>Software versions</title>
        <p>Quarto
  (<xref alt="Allaire et al., 2025" rid="ref-allaireQuarto2025-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Allaire
  et al., 2025</xref>) version 1.7.32 and the extension apaquarto
  (<xref alt="Schneider, 2025" rid="ref-schneiderApaquarto2025-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Schneider,
  2025</xref>) were used together with RStudio
  (<xref alt="Posit team, 2025" rid="ref-positRstudio2025-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Posit
  team, 2025</xref>) to build the manuscript and the manuscript website.
  R (Version 4.5.1;
  <xref alt="R Core Team, 2025b" rid="ref-R-base-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">R Core
  Team, 2025b</xref>) and the R-packages <italic>corx</italic> (Version
  1.0.7.2;
  <xref alt="Conigrave, 2023" rid="ref-R-corx-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Conigrave,
  2023</xref>), <italic>dplyr</italic> (Version 1.1.4;
  <xref alt="Wickham et al., 2023" rid="ref-R-dplyr-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Wickham
  et al., 2023</xref>), <italic>flextable</italic> (Version 0.9.9;
  <xref alt="Gohel &amp; Skintzos, 2024" rid="ref-R-flextable-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Gohel
  &amp; Skintzos, 2024</xref>), <italic>forcats</italic> (Version 1.0.0;
  <xref alt="Wickham, 2023a" rid="ref-R-forcats-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Wickham,
  2023a</xref>), <italic>foreign</italic> (Version 0.8.90;
  <xref alt="R Core Team, 2025a" rid="ref-R-foreign-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">R
  Core Team, 2025a</xref>), <italic>ggplot2</italic> (Version 3.5.2;
  <xref alt="Wickham, 2016" rid="ref-R-ggplot2-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Wickham,
  2016</xref>), <italic>lavaan</italic> (Version 0.6.19;
  <xref alt="Rosseel, 2012" rid="ref-R-lavaan-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Rosseel,
  2012</xref>), <italic>lubridate</italic> (Version 1.9.4;
  <xref alt="Grolemund &amp; Wickham, 2011" rid="ref-R-lubridate-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Grolemund
  &amp; Wickham, 2011</xref>), <italic>MBESS</italic> (Version 4.9.3;
  <xref alt="Kelley, 2023" rid="ref-R-MBESS-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Kelley,
  2023</xref>), <italic>papaja</italic> (Version 0.1.3;
  <xref alt="Aust &amp; Barth, 2024" rid="ref-R-papaja-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Aust
  &amp; Barth, 2024</xref>), <italic>psych</italic> (Version 2.5.6;
  <xref alt="William Revelle, 2025" rid="ref-R-psych-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">William
  Revelle, 2025</xref>), <italic>purrr</italic> (Version 1.1.0;
  <xref alt="Wickham &amp; Henry, 2025" rid="ref-R-purrr-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Wickham
  &amp; Henry, 2025</xref>), <italic>readr</italic> (Version 2.1.5;
  <xref alt="Wickham, Hester, et al., 2024" rid="ref-R-readr-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Wickham,
  Hester, et al., 2024</xref>), <italic>semTools</italic> (Version
  0.5.7;
  <xref alt="Jorgensen et al., 2025" rid="ref-R-semTools-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Jorgensen
  et al., 2025</xref>), <italic>stringr</italic> (Version 1.5.1;
  <xref alt="Wickham, 2023b" rid="ref-R-stringr-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Wickham,
  2023b</xref>), <italic>tibble</italic> (Version 3.3.0;
  <xref alt="Müller &amp; Wickham, 2023" rid="ref-R-tibble-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Müller
  &amp; Wickham, 2023</xref>), <italic>tidyr</italic> (Version 1.3.1;
  <xref alt="Wickham, Vaughan, et al., 2024" rid="ref-R-tidyr-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Wickham,
  Vaughan, et al., 2024</xref>), <italic>tidyverse</italic> (Version
  2.0.0;
  <xref alt="Wickham et al., 2019" rid="ref-R-tidyverse-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Wickham
  et al., 2019</xref>) and <italic>tinylabels</italic> (Version 0.2.5;
  <xref alt="Barth, 2025" rid="ref-R-tinylabels-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Barth,
  2025</xref>) were used for data analysis.
  Some dependencies are not included in this list but can be found in
  the <monospace>renv.lock</monospace> file in our online
  repository.</p>
      </sec>
    </body>
    <back>
      <ref-list>
        <title/>
        <ref id="ref-maulRethinking2017-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Maul</surname>
                <given-names>Andrew</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Rethinking traditional methods of survey validation</article-title>
            <source>Measurement: Interdisciplinary Research and Perspectives</source>
            <publisher-name>Routledge</publisher-name>
            <year iso-8601-date="2017">2017</year>
            <volume>15</volume>
            <issue>2</issue>
            <uri>https://doi.org/10.1080/15366367.2017.1348108</uri>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/15366367.2017.1348108</pub-id>
            <fpage>51</fpage>
            <lpage>69</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-eichhornItem2019-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="thesis">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Eichhorn</surname>
                <given-names>Kathryn</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Item und skala: Empirische untersuchungen zur gültigkeit psychologischer messungen anhand physikalischer merkmale</article-title>
            <publisher-name>Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München</publisher-name>
            <year iso-8601-date="2019">2019</year>
            <uri>http://nbn-resolving.de/urn:nbn:de:bvb:19-236286</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-schneiderApaquarto2025-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="software">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Schneider</surname>
                <given-names>William Joel</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>apaquarto</article-title>
            <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
            <uri>https://github.com/wjschne/apaquarto</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-positRstudio2025-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <string-name>Posit team</string-name>
            </person-group>
            <source>RStudio: Integrated development environment for r</source>
            <publisher-name>Posit Software, PBC</publisher-name>
            <publisher-loc>Boston, MA</publisher-loc>
            <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
            <uri>http://www.posit.co/</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-allaireQuarto2025-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="software">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Allaire</surname>
                <given-names>J. J.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Teague</surname>
                <given-names>Charles</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Scheidegger</surname>
                <given-names>Carlos</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Xie</surname>
                <given-names>Yihui</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Dervieux</surname>
                <given-names>Christophe</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Woodhull</surname>
                <given-names>Gordon</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Quarto</article-title>
            <year iso-8601-date="2025-04">2025</year>
            <month>04</month>
            <uri>https://github.com/quarto-dev/quarto-cli</uri>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.5960048</pub-id>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-bortolottiRelevanceAdvantagesUsing2013-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Bortolotti</surname>
                <given-names>Silvana Ligia Vincenzi</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Tezza</surname>
                <given-names>Rafael</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>De Andrade</surname>
                <given-names>Dalton Francisco</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Bornia</surname>
                <given-names>Antonio Cezar</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>De Sousa Júnior</surname>
                <given-names>Afonso Farias</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Relevance and advantages of using the item response theory</article-title>
            <source>Quality &amp; Quantity</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2013-06">2013</year>
            <month>06</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>47</volume>
            <issue>4</issue>
            <issn>0033-5177, 1573-7845</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11135-012-9684-5</pub-id>
            <fpage>2341</fpage>
            <lpage>2360</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-bradleyRatingScalesSurvey2015-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Bradley</surname>
                <given-names>Kelly D.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Peabody</surname>
                <given-names>Michael R.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Akers</surname>
                <given-names>Kathryn S.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Knutson</surname>
                <given-names>Nichole M.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Rating Scales in Survey Research: Using the Rasch model to illustrate the middle category measurement flaw</article-title>
            <source>Survey Practice</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2015-05">2015</year>
            <month>05</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>8</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>2168-0094</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.29115/SP-2015-0001</pub-id>
            <fpage>1</fpage>
            <lpage>12</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-broughtonPrototypeStrategyConstruction1984-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Broughton</surname>
                <given-names>Ross</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>A prototype strategy for construction of personality scales.</article-title>
            <source>Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="1984-12">1984</year>
            <month>12</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>47</volume>
            <issue>6</issue>
            <issn>1939-1315, 0022-3514</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.47.6.1334</pub-id>
            <fpage>1334</fpage>
            <lpage>1346</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-burischApproachesPersonalityInventory1984-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Burisch</surname>
                <given-names>Matthias</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Approaches to personality inventory construction: A comparison of merits.</article-title>
            <source>American Psychologist</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="1984-03">1984</year>
            <month>03</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>39</volume>
            <issue>3</issue>
            <issn>1935-990X, 0003-066X</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1037/0003-066X.39.3.214</pub-id>
            <fpage>214</fpage>
            <lpage>227</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-debelakTestingLocalIndependence2020-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Debelak</surname>
                <given-names>Rudolf</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Koller</surname>
                <given-names>Ingrid</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Testing the Local Independence Assumption of the Rasch Model With Q3 -Based Nonparametric Model Tests</article-title>
            <source>Applied Psychological Measurement</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2020-03">2020</year>
            <month>03</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>44</volume>
            <issue>2</issue>
            <issn>0146-6216, 1552-3497</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/0146621619835501</pub-id>
            <fpage>103</fpage>
            <lpage>117</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-faulbaumWasIstGute2009-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Faulbaum</surname>
                <given-names>Frank</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Prüfer</surname>
                <given-names>Peter</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Rexroth</surname>
                <given-names>Margrit</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Was ist eine gute Frage?</source>
            <publisher-name>VS Verlag für Sozialwissenschaften</publisher-name>
            <publisher-loc>Wiesbaden</publisher-loc>
            <year iso-8601-date="2009">2009</year>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <isbn>978-3-531-15824-2 978-3-531-91441-1</isbn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/978-3-531-91441-1</pub-id>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-goretzkoEvaluatingModelFit2024-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Goretzko</surname>
                <given-names>David</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Siemund</surname>
                <given-names>Karik</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Sterner</surname>
                <given-names>Philipp</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Evaluating Model Fit of Measurement Models in Confirmatory Factor Analysis</article-title>
            <source>Educational and Psychological Measurement</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2024-02">2024</year>
            <month>02</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>84</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>0013-1644, 1552-3888</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/00131644231163813</pub-id>
            <fpage>123</fpage>
            <lpage>144</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-hilbertInfluenceResponseFormat2016-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Hilbert</surname>
                <given-names>Sven</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Küchenhoff</surname>
                <given-names>Helmut</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Sarubin</surname>
                <given-names>Nina</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Toyo Nakagawa</surname>
                <given-names>Tristan</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Bühner</surname>
                <given-names>Markus</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>The influence of the response format in a personality questionnaire: An analysis of a dichotomous, a Likert-type, and a visual analogue scale</article-title>
            <source>TPM - Testing, Psychometrics, Methodology in Applied Psychology</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2016">2016</year>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>23</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>1972-6325</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4473/TPM23.1.1</pub-id>
            <fpage>3</fpage>
            <lpage>24</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-hilbertWhatMeasureEmpirical2022-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Hilbert</surname>
                <given-names>Sven</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Pargent</surname>
                <given-names>Florian</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Kraus</surname>
                <given-names>Elisabeth</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Naumann</surname>
                <given-names>Felix</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Eichhorn</surname>
                <given-names>Kathryn</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Ungar</surname>
                <given-names>Patrizia</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Bühner</surname>
                <given-names>Markus</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>What’s the measure? An empirical investigation of self-ratings on response scales</article-title>
            <source>International Journal of Social Research Methodology</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2022-01">2022</year>
            <month>01</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>25</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>1364-5579, 1464-5300</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/13645579.2020.1839163</pub-id>
            <fpage>59</fpage>
            <lpage>78</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-leeSearchOptimalNumber2014-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Lee</surname>
                <given-names>Jihyun</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Paek</surname>
                <given-names>Insu</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>In Search of the Optimal Number of Response Categories in a Rating Scale</article-title>
            <source>Journal of Psychoeducational Assessment</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2014-10">2014</year>
            <month>10</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>32</volume>
            <issue>7</issue>
            <issn>0734-2829, 1557-5144</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/0734282914522200</pub-id>
            <fpage>663</fpage>
            <lpage>673</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-lordStatisticalTheoriesMental1968-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Lord</surname>
                <given-names>Frederic M.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Novick</surname>
                <given-names>Melvin R.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Birnbaum</surname>
                <given-names>Allan</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Lord</surname>
                <given-names>Frederic M.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Statistical theories of mental test scores</source>
            <publisher-name>Addison-Wesley</publisher-name>
            <publisher-loc>Reading, Mass.</publisher-loc>
            <year iso-8601-date="1968">1968</year>
            <edition>2. print</edition>
            <isbn>978-0-201-04310-5</isbn>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-martinAnthropometrieAnleitungSelbstaendigen1929-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Martin</surname>
                <given-names>Rudolf</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Anthropometrie: Anleitung Zu Selbständigen Anthropologischen Erhebungen</source>
            <publisher-name>Springer Berlin / Heidelberg</publisher-name>
            <publisher-loc>Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher-loc>
            <year iso-8601-date="1929">1929</year>
            <edition>2nd ed</edition>
            <isbn>978-3-662-31474-6 978-3-662-31681-8</isbn>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-masudaRespondentsLowMotivation2017-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Masuda</surname>
                <given-names>Shinya</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Sakagami</surname>
                <given-names>Takayuki</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Kawabata</surname>
                <given-names>Hideaki</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Kijima</surname>
                <given-names>Nobuhiko</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Hoshino</surname>
                <given-names>Takahiro</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Respondents with low motivation tend to choose middle category: Survey questions on happiness in Japan</article-title>
            <source>Behaviormetrika</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2017-07">2017</year>
            <month>07</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>44</volume>
            <issue>2</issue>
            <issn>0385-7417, 1349-6964</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s41237-017-0026-8</pub-id>
            <fpage>593</fpage>
            <lpage>605</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-mccrearyGenderAgeDifferences2002-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>McCreary</surname>
                <given-names>Donald</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Gender and Age Differences in the Relationship Between Body Mass Index and Perceived Weight: Exploring the Paradox</article-title>
            <source>International Journal of Men’s Health</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2002-01">2002</year>
            <month>01</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>1</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>1532-6306, 1933-0278</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3149/jmh.0101.31</pub-id>
            <fpage>31</fpage>
            <lpage>42</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-mcneishThornyRelationMeasurement2018-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>McNeish</surname>
                <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>An</surname>
                <given-names>Ji</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Hancock</surname>
                <given-names>Gregory R.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>The Thorny Relation Between Measurement Quality and Fit Index Cutoffs in Latent Variable Models</article-title>
            <source>Journal of Personality Assessment</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2018-01">2018</year>
            <month>01</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>100</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>0022-3891, 1532-7752</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/00223891.2017.1281286</pub-id>
            <fpage>43</fpage>
            <lpage>52</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-montepareYouReOnly1989-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Montepare</surname>
                <given-names>Joann M.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Lachman</surname>
                <given-names>Margie E.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>"You’re only as old as you feel": Self-perceptions of age, fears of aging, and life satisfaction from adolescence to old age.</article-title>
            <source>Psychology and Aging</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="1989-03">1989</year>
            <month>03</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>4</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>1939-1498, 0882-7974</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1037/0882-7974.4.1.73</pub-id>
            <fpage>73</fpage>
            <lpage>78</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-pargentCanMakeIt2019-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Pargent</surname>
                <given-names>Florian</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Hilbert</surname>
                <given-names>Sven</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Eichhorn</surname>
                <given-names>Kathryn</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Bühner</surname>
                <given-names>Markus</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Can’t Make it Better nor Worse: An Empirical Study About the Effectiveness of General Rules of Item Construction on Psychometric Properties</article-title>
            <source>European Journal of Psychological Assessment</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2019-11">2019</year>
            <month>11</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>35</volume>
            <issue>6</issue>
            <issn>1015-5759, 2151-2426</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1027/1015-5759/a000471</pub-id>
            <fpage>891</fpage>
            <lpage>899</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-prestonOptimalNumberResponse2000-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Preston</surname>
                <given-names>Carolyn C</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Colman</surname>
                <given-names>Andrew M</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Optimal number of response categories in rating scales: Reliability, validity, discriminating power, and respondent preferences</article-title>
            <source>Acta Psychologica</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2000-03">2000</year>
            <month>03</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>104</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>00016918</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0001-6918(99)00050-5</pub-id>
            <fpage>1</fpage>
            <lpage>15</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-revillaChoosingNumberCategories2014-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Revilla</surname>
                <given-names>Melanie A.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Saris</surname>
                <given-names>Willem E.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Krosnick</surname>
                <given-names>Jon A.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Choosing the Number of Categories in Agree–Disagree Scales</article-title>
            <source>Sociological Methods &amp; Research</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2014-02">2014</year>
            <month>02</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>43</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>0049-1241, 1552-8294</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/0049124113509605</pub-id>
            <fpage>73</fpage>
            <lpage>97</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-schwallDefiningAgeUsing2012-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Schwall</surname>
                <given-names>Alexander R.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Defining Age and Using Age-Relevant Constructs</source>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
            <year iso-8601-date="2012-03">2012</year>
            <month>03</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/oxfordhb/9780195385052.013.0080</pub-id>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-vanderlindenUnidimensionalLogisticResponse2016-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="chapter">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Van der Linden</surname>
                <given-names>Wim J.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Unidimensional logistic response models</article-title>
            <source>Handbook of item response theory, volume one: models</source>
            <person-group person-group-type="editor">
              <name>
                <surname>Van der Linden</surname>
                <given-names>Wim J.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <publisher-name>Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC</publisher-name>
            <publisher-loc>Boca Raton, FL</publisher-loc>
            <year iso-8601-date="2016">2016</year>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1201/9781315374512</pub-id>
            <fpage>13</fpage>
            <lpage>30</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-weijtersEffectRatingScale2010-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Weijters</surname>
                <given-names>Bert</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Cabooter</surname>
                <given-names>Elke</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Schillewaert</surname>
                <given-names>Niels</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>The effect of rating scale format on response styles: The number of response categories and response category labels</article-title>
            <source>International Journal of Research in Marketing</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2010-09">2010</year>
            <month>09</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>27</volume>
            <issue>3</issue>
            <issn>01678116</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ijresmar.2010.02.004</pub-id>
            <fpage>236</fpage>
            <lpage>247</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-willisCognitiveInterviewing2005-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Willis</surname>
                <given-names>Gordon</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Cognitive Interviewing</source>
            <publisher-name>SAGE Publications, Inc.</publisher-name>
            <publisher-loc>2455 Teller Road, Thousand Oaks California 91320 United States of America</publisher-loc>
            <year iso-8601-date="2005">2005</year>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <isbn>978-0-7619-2804-1 978-1-4129-8365-5</isbn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4135/9781412983655</pub-id>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-zijlmansItemScoreReliabilitySelection2019-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Zijlmans</surname>
                <given-names>Eva A. O.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Tijmstra</surname>
                <given-names>Jesper</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Van Der Ark</surname>
                <given-names>L. Andries</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Sijtsma</surname>
                <given-names>Klaas</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Item-Score Reliability as a Selection Tool in Test Construction</article-title>
            <source>Frontiers in Psychology</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2019-01">2019</year>
            <month>01</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2025-06-03">2025</year>
              <month>06</month>
              <day>03</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>9</volume>
            <issn>1664-1078</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2018.02298</pub-id>
            <fpage>2298</fpage>
            <lpage/>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-barakCognitiveAgeNonchronological1981-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Barak</surname>
                <given-names>Benny</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Schiffman</surname>
                <given-names>Leon G.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Cognitive age: A nonchronological age variable.</article-title>
            <source>Advances in Consumer Research</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="1981">1981</year>
            <volume>8</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>0098-9258</issn>
            <fpage>602</fpage>
            <lpage>606</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-tenholtScaleConstructionEvaluation2010-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Holt</surname>
                <given-names>Janke C. ten</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Duijn</surname>
                <given-names>Marijtje A. J. van</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Boomsma</surname>
                <given-names>Anne</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Scale construction and evaluation in practice: A review of factor analysis versus item response theory applications.</article-title>
            <source>Psychological Test and Assessment Modeling</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2010">2010</year>
            <volume>52</volume>
            <issue>3</issue>
            <issn>2190-0507(Electronic),2190-0493(Print)</issn>
            <fpage>272</fpage>
            <lpage>297</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-prueferVerfahrenEvaluationSurvey1996-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Prüfer</surname>
                <given-names>Peter</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Rexroth</surname>
                <given-names>Margrit</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Verfahren zur evaluation von survey-fragen: Ein überblick</source>
            <publisher-name>Zentrum für Umfragen, Methoden und Analysen -ZUMA-</publisher-name>
            <publisher-loc>Mannheim</publisher-loc>
            <year iso-8601-date="1996">1996</year>
            <volume>1996/05</volume>
            <fpage>34</fpage>
            <lpage/>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-prueferKognitiveInterviews2005-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Prüfer</surname>
                <given-names>Peter</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Rexroth</surname>
                <given-names>Margrit</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Kognitive interviews</source>
            <publisher-name>Zentrum für Umfragen, Methoden und Analysen -ZUMA-</publisher-name>
            <publisher-loc>Mannheim</publisher-loc>
            <year iso-8601-date="2005">2005</year>
            <volume>15</volume>
            <fpage>26</fpage>
            <lpage/>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-base-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <string-name>R Core Team</string-name>
            </person-group>
            <source>R: A language and environment for statistical computing</source>
            <publisher-name>R Foundation for Statistical Computing</publisher-name>
            <publisher-loc>Vienna, Austria</publisher-loc>
            <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
            <uri>https://www.R-project.org/</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-corx-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Conigrave</surname>
                <given-names>James</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Corx: Create and format correlation matrices</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
            <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=corx</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-dplyr-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Wickham</surname>
                <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>François</surname>
                <given-names>Romain</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Henry</surname>
                <given-names>Lionel</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Müller</surname>
                <given-names>Kirill</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Vaughan</surname>
                <given-names>Davis</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Dplyr: A grammar of data manipulation</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
            <uri>https://dplyr.tidyverse.org</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-forcats-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Wickham</surname>
                <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Forcats: Tools for working with categorical variables (factors)</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
            <uri>https://forcats.tidyverse.org/</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-foreign-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <string-name>R Core Team</string-name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Foreign: Read data stored by ’minitab’, ’s’, ’SAS’, ’SPSS’, ’stata’, ’systat’, ’weka’, ’dBase’, ...</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
            <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=foreign</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-ggplot2-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Wickham</surname>
                <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>ggplot2: Elegant graphics for data analysis</source>
            <publisher-name>Springer-Verlag New York</publisher-name>
            <year iso-8601-date="2016">2016</year>
            <isbn>978-3-319-24277-4</isbn>
            <uri>https://ggplot2.tidyverse.org</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-lavaan-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Rosseel</surname>
                <given-names>Yves</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>lavaan: An R package for structural equation modeling</article-title>
            <source>Journal of Statistical Software</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2012">2012</year>
            <volume>48</volume>
            <issue>2</issue>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.18637/jss.v048.i02</pub-id>
            <fpage>1</fpage>
            <lpage>36</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-lubridate-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Grolemund</surname>
                <given-names>Garrett</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Wickham</surname>
                <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Dates and times made easy with lubridate</article-title>
            <source>Journal of Statistical Software</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2011">2011</year>
            <volume>40</volume>
            <issue>3</issue>
            <uri>https://www.jstatsoft.org/v40/i03/</uri>
            <fpage>1</fpage>
            <lpage>25</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-MBESS-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Kelley</surname>
                <given-names>Ken</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>MBESS: The MBESS r package</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
            <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=MBESS</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-purrr-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Wickham</surname>
                <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Henry</surname>
                <given-names>Lionel</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Purrr: Functional programming tools</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
            <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=purrr</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-readr-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Wickham</surname>
                <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Hester</surname>
                <given-names>Jim</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Bryan</surname>
                <given-names>Jennifer</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Readr: Read rectangular text data</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
            <uri>https://readr.tidyverse.org</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-semTools-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Jorgensen</surname>
                <given-names>Terrence D.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Pornprasertmanit</surname>
                <given-names>Sunthud</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Schoemann</surname>
                <given-names>Alexander M.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Rosseel</surname>
                <given-names>Yves</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>semTools: Useful tools for structural equation modeling</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
            <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=semTools</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-stringr-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Wickham</surname>
                <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Stringr: Simple, consistent wrappers for common string operations</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
            <uri>https://stringr.tidyverse.org</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-tibble-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Müller</surname>
                <given-names>Kirill</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Wickham</surname>
                <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Tibble: Simple data frames</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2023">2023</year>
            <uri>https://tibble.tidyverse.org/</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-tidyr-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Wickham</surname>
                <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Vaughan</surname>
                <given-names>Davis</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Girlich</surname>
                <given-names>Maximilian</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Tidyr: Tidy messy data</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
            <uri>https://tidyr.tidyverse.org</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-tidyverse-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Wickham</surname>
                <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Averick</surname>
                <given-names>Mara</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Bryan</surname>
                <given-names>Jennifer</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Chang</surname>
                <given-names>Winston</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>McGowan</surname>
                <given-names>Lucy D’Agostino</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>François</surname>
                <given-names>Romain</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Grolemund</surname>
                <given-names>Garrett</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Hayes</surname>
                <given-names>Alex</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Henry</surname>
                <given-names>Lionel</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Hester</surname>
                <given-names>Jim</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Kuhn</surname>
                <given-names>Max</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Pedersen</surname>
                <given-names>Thomas Lin</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Miller</surname>
                <given-names>Evan</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Bache</surname>
                <given-names>Stephan Milton</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Müller</surname>
                <given-names>Kirill</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Ooms</surname>
                <given-names>Jeroen</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Robinson</surname>
                <given-names>David</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Seidel</surname>
                <given-names>Dana Paige</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Spinu</surname>
                <given-names>Vitalie</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Takahashi</surname>
                <given-names>Kohske</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Vaughan</surname>
                <given-names>Davis</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Wilke</surname>
                <given-names>Claus</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Woo</surname>
                <given-names>Kara</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Yutani</surname>
                <given-names>Hiroaki</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Welcome to the tidyverse</article-title>
            <source>Journal of Open Source Software</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2019">2019</year>
            <volume>4</volume>
            <issue>43</issue>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.21105/joss.01686</pub-id>
            <fpage>1686</fpage>
            <lpage/>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-flextable-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Gohel</surname>
                <given-names>David</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Skintzos</surname>
                <given-names>Panagiotis</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Flextable: Functions for tabular reporting</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
            <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=flextable</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-papaja-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Aust</surname>
                <given-names>Frederik</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Barth</surname>
                <given-names>Marius</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>papaja: Prepare reproducible APA journal articles with R Markdown</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
            <uri>https://github.com/crsh/papaja</uri>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.32614/CRAN.package.papaja</pub-id>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-tinylabels-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Barth</surname>
                <given-names>Marius</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <source>tinylabels: Lightweight variable labels</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
            <uri>https://cran.r-project.org/package=tinylabels</uri>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.32614/CRAN.package.tinylabels</pub-id>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-R-psych-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="book">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <string-name>William Revelle</string-name>
            </person-group>
            <source>Psych: Procedures for psychological, psychometric, and personality research</source>
            <publisher-name>Northwestern University</publisher-name>
            <publisher-loc>Evanston, Illinois</publisher-loc>
            <year iso-8601-date="2025">2025</year>
            <uri>https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=psych</uri>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
      <fn-group>
        <fn id="fn1-nb-article">
          <label>1</label>
          <p>The data presented in this manuscript has
    previously been analyzed in the German dissertation thesis of the
    first author
    (<xref alt="Eichhorn, 2019" rid="ref-eichhornItem2019-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Eichhorn,
    2019</xref>). As part of the dissertation, a preregistration was
    published at
    <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://osf.io/cz3uv/?view_only=9cac02db231b48629fea9ae53c3038b9">https://osf.io/cz3uv/?view_only=9cac02db231b48629fea9ae53c3038b9</ext-link>
    that differs from the analyses reported in the current publication.
    The results of the preregistered analyses are reported in Eichhorn
    (<xref alt="2019" rid="ref-eichhornItem2019-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>).</p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="fn2-nb-article">
          <label>2</label>
          <p>Compared to the pilot test, one height and one
    weight item were slightly reworded to simplify the wording and
    reduce similarities with other items in the scale.</p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="fn3-nb-article">
          <label>3</label>
          <p>Note that although the models for height
    (controlling for the physical item and gender) estimated some
    absolute standardized loadings greater than 1, all models converged
    and the diagnostics used by the <italic>lavaan</italic> package
    (<xref alt="Rosseel, 2012" rid="ref-R-lavaan-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Rosseel,
    2012</xref>) did not report any problems.</p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    </back>
  </sub-article>
  <!-- (F2ED4C6E)[nb-1]:/Users/florianpargent/Documents/Forschung/gold-standard-items/analysis/primary_analyses.qmd -->
  <!-- (F2ED4C6E)[nb-2]:/Users/florianpargent/Documents/Forschung/gold-standard-items/analysis/secondary_analyses.qmd -->
  <!-- (F2ED4C6E)[nb-3]:/Users/florianpargent/Documents/Forschung/gold-standard-items/analysis/tertiary_analyses.qmd -->
</article>
